等一下，別射
Okay, hold on, don't shoot.
-看到目標了嗎？ -嗯
- You see where you're going? - Mm-hmm.
好
Okay.
現在想想怎麼射中
Now, let's worry about how you get there.
腳得移過來
Gotta move your foot here.
腳尖向這邊
Point your toe this way.
屁股，挺胸
Your hips here.
好了嗎？
Okay?
-看得見嗎？ -可以
- Can you see? - Yeah.
-確定？ -嗯
- Are you sure? - Mm-hmm.
現在呢？看得見嗎？
How about now? Can you see now?
-看不見 -這樣呢？
- No. - How about now?
好
All right.
準備，用三根手指頭
Ready? Three fingers.
漂亮
Nice!
投得真棒，孩子
Nice throw, kiddo.
接住
Here you go.
你們要美乃滋還是芥末醬？
Hey, you guys want mayo? Or mustard?
還是都要？
Or both?
哪有人熱狗加美乃滋？
Who puts mayo on a hot dog?
妳弟弟吧
Probably your brothers.
兩份加芥末醬，謝了，媽媽
Uh, two mustard, please! Thanks, Mama.
知道了
Got it!
奈特，美乃滋還是芥末醬？
Nate, mayo or mustard?
番茄醬呢？
How about ketchup?
好，也有番茄醬
Or ketchup. I got ketchup, too.
注意手肘
Mind your elbow.
好眼力
Good job, hawk-eye.
去拔箭
Go get your arrow.
大家過來
Hey, guys!
練習夠了，吃東西
Enough practice. Soup's on!
好
All right.
馬上來，我們餓了
We're coming. We're hungry.
萊拉，走吧
Lila, let's go.
萊拉？
Lila?
親愛的？
Honey?
老婆？
Hey, babe?
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-
老婆？
Babe?
兒子！
Boys!
蘿拉！
Laura!
妳不必這樣
You don't need to do that.
只要保持不動就好
Because, uh, you're just holding the position.
對
Oh, yeah.
差一點
That was close.
得分，現在一比一
That's a goal. We are now one a piece.
我想再試試看
I would like to try again.
我們平手，緊張嗎？
We're tied up. Feel the tension?
好玩
It's fun.
爛死了，現在妳有機會贏
That was terrible. Now you have a chance to win.
妳贏了
And you've won.
恭喜
Congratulations.
公平競爭
Fair game.
可敬的對手
Good sport.
開心嗎？
You have fun?
很好玩
It was fun.
啟動了嗎？
This thing on?
波茲小姐，小辣椒
Hey, Miss Potts. Pep.
如果妳找到這段錄影
If you find this recording...
別放到社群媒體上
don't post it on social media.
它會讓人大飆淚
It's gonna be a real tearjerker.
不知道妳會不會看到這些影片
I don't know if you're ever gonna see these.
不知道妳是否還…
I don't even know if you're still...
天啊，希望如此
Oh, God, I hope so.
今天是第21天
Today's day 21.
不，第22天
No, uh, 22.
要不是因為盯著無垠太空
You know, if it wasn't for the existential terror...
產生存在恐懼，我今天會好過點
of staring into the literal void of space, I'd say I'm feeling a little better today.
感染快好了，多虧裡面那個藍臉魔王
Infection's run its course, thanks to the Blue Meanie back there.
妳會很喜歡她的
Oh, you'd love her.
非常務實
Very practical.
只有一點虐待狂
Only a tiny bit sadistic.
燃料電池在戰役中受損
So, the fuel cells were cracked during battle...
我們設法反轉離子電荷
and we figured out a way to reverse the ion charge...
多爭取了48小時飛行時間
and bought ourselves about 48 hours of flight time.
但現在陷入絕境
Uh, but it's now dead in the water.
最近的7-11在一千光年以外
Thousand light years from the nearest 7-Eleven.
氧氣明早會用完
Oxygen will run out tomorrow morning...
就這樣了
and that'll be it.
小辣椒，我說過不再有驚人之舉
Pep, I know I said no more surprises...
但我真的希望再做最後一次
but I gotta say I was really hoping to pull off one last one.
可是看起來…
But it looks like...
妳也知道現在的情況
Well, you know what it looks like.
不要難過
Don't feel bad about this.
如果妳悲痛個幾星期
I mean, actually, if you grovel for a couple weeks...
然後帶著強烈罪惡感過日子…
and then move on with enormous guilt...
我應該躺一下，閉目養神
I should probably lie down for a minute. Go rest my eyes.
請妳瞭解
Please know...
等我慢慢睡著，就會像最近的每個夜晚
when I drift off, it'll be like every night lately.
我很好，好得不得了
I'm fine. Totally fine.
我常夢見妳
I dream about you.
自始至終都是妳
Because it's always you.
我阻止不了他
Couldn't stop him.
我也沒辦法
Neither could I.
等一下
Hang on.
我失去了那小子
I lost the kid.
東尼，我們輸了
Tony, we lost.
是不是…
Is, uh...?
我的天啊
- Oh, good. - Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
沒事
It's okay.
薩諾斯來到地球已經23天
It's been 23 days since Thanos came to Earth.
（史蒂芬史傳奇，失蹤）
（山姆威爾森，失蹤）
各國政府分崩離析
World governments are
（汪達麥西莫夫，失蹤）
in pieces.
還在運作的政府
The parts that are still working...
（史考特朗恩，失蹤）
正試圖統計人數，看來他…
...are trying to take a census and it looks like he did...
他說到做到
He did exactly what he said he was gonna do.
薩諾斯殲滅了…
Thanos wiped out...
（尼克福瑞，失蹤）
世上一半的生物
...50% of all living creatures.
他現在在哪裡？
Where is he now? Where?
不知道
We don't know.
他打開一個入口，走了進去
He just opened a portal and walked through.
他怎麼了？
What's wrong with him?
他很火大
Oh, he's pissed.
覺得自己失敗了
He thinks he failed.
當然是那樣沒錯
Which, of course, he did...
但大家不都如此嗎？
but there's a lot of that going around, ain't there?
說真的，我剛剛還以為你是填充玩具
Honestly, until this exact second I thought you were a Build-A-Bear.
也許我是
Maybe I am.
我們找了薩諾斯三星期
We've been hunting Thanos for three weeks now.
深度太空掃描
Deep space scans...
還有衛星，一無所獲
and satellites, and we got nothing.
東尼，你對抗過他
Tony, you fought him.
誰告訴你的？
Who told you that?
我沒有
I didn't fight him.
他徹底擊垮我
No, he wiped my face with a planet...
那個紐約魔術師奉上寶石
while the Bleecker Street magician gave away the store.
沒有對抗，他根本打不垮
That's what happened. There was no fight, 'cause he's not beatable.
他有給你線索或座標嗎？
Did he give you any clues, any coordinates, anything?
Uh...
幾年前我就料到了
I saw this coming a few years back.
我看到一個景象，卻不願相信
I had a vision. I didn't wanna believe it.
以為自己在作夢
Thought I was dreaming.
東尼，我需要你專注點
Tony, I'm gonna need you to focus.
當時我需要你
And I needed you.
過去式
As in, past tense.
那比你需要的更重要，太遲了
That trumps what you need. It's too late, buddy.
抱歉
Sorry.
我需要什麼呢？刮鬍子
You know what I need? I need a shave.
我記得告訴你們…
And I believe I remember telling all youse...
東尼…
Tony, Tony!
無論死活，我們需要一套全球防衛機制
...alive and otherwise, that what we needed was a suit of armour around the world.
記得嗎？無論它是否影響我們寶貴的自由
Remember that? Whether it impacted our precious freedoms or not.
那才是我們需要的
That's what we needed.
結果無效，是吧？
Well, that didn't work out, did it?
我說我們會輸
I said we'd lose.
你說要輸也是一起輸
You said, "We'll do that together, too."
結果呢，隊長？
And guess what, Cap?
我們輸了
We lost.
你卻不在場
And you weren't there.
我們就是這德行
But that's what we do, right?
事後只會說我們是復仇者聯盟
Our best work after the fact? We're the "Avengers."
我們是復仇者聯盟，不是預防者聯盟
We're the "Avengers," not the "Pre-vengers."
-好啦 -對吧？
- Okay. - Right?
你表達得很清楚了，坐下
You made your point. Just sit down, okay?
不，我要講重點了
Okay. No, no, here's my point. You know what?
-她很厲害 -你病了，坐下
- She's great by the way. - Tony, you're sick. Sit down.
我們需要妳，妳是新血
We need you. You're new blood.
我們都是老屁股，我沒東西給你，隊長
Bunch of tired old mules. I got nothing for you, Cap.
我沒有座標
I got no coordinates...
沒線索，沒策略，沒選擇
no clues, no strategies, no options.
零，鴨蛋，屁都沒有
Zero. Zip. Nada.
沒有信任，騙子
No trust, liar.
拿去
Here, take this.
找到他，戴上去
You find him, you put that on...
躲起來
you hide.
-東尼 -我很好
- Tony! - I'm fine.
讓我…
Let me...
布魯斯幫他打了鎮靜劑
Bruce gave him a sedative.
他應該今天都不會醒
He's gonna probably be out for the rest of the day.
你們照顧他
You guys take care of him...
我再帶梭爾人的仙丹回來
and I'll bring him a Xorrian elixir when I come back.
妳要去哪？
Where are you going?
幹掉薩諾斯
To kill Thanos.
喂
Hey.
我們通常集體行動
You know, we usually work as a team here...
其實現在士氣低落
and, uh, between you and I, morale's a little fragile.
太空固然是妳的戰場，但這也是我們的戰役
We realize up there is more your territory, but this is our fight, too.
妳知道他的下落嗎？
You even know where he is?
我認識的人可能知道
I know people who might.
不必麻煩了
Don't bother.
我能告訴你們薩諾斯在哪
I can tell you where Thanos is.
薩諾斯花了很長時間使我更趨完美
Thanos spent a long time trying to perfect me.
他常提到他的遠大計劃
And when he worked, he talked about his Great Plan.
我就算支離破碎，也想討好他
Even disassembled, I wanted to please him.
我會問他
I'd ask...
他計畫完成後，我們會去哪裡？
where would we go once his plan was complete?
他的答案始終如一
And his answer was always the same.
去花園
"To the Garden."
真可愛，薩諾斯有養老計畫
That's cute. Thanos has a retirement plan.
所以他在哪裡？
So, where is he?
薩諾斯一彈指
When Thanos snapped his fingers...
地球成了一股超強電力突波的中心點
Earth became ground zero for a power surge of ridiculously cosmic proportions.
沒人見過那樣的奇景
No one's ever seen anything like it.
直到兩天前
Until two days ago...
在這個星球上
on this planet.
薩諾斯在那裡
Thanos is there.
他又運用了無限寶石
He used the stones again.
喂…
Hey, hey, hey.
我們人手不足
We'd be going in shorthanded, you know?
無限寶石還在他手上
Look, he's still got the stones, so...
我們去拿
So, let's get 'em.
用它們把所有人救回來
Use them to bring everyone back.
就那樣？
Just like that?
對，就那樣
Yeah. Just like that.
即便逆轉的機會微乎其微
Even if there's a small chance that we can undo this...
為了其他人，我們也該放手一搏
I mean, we owe it to everyone who's not in this room to try.
如果這麼做，如何知道結果會有所不同？
If we do this, how do we know it's gonna end any differently than it did before?
因為以前你們沒有我
Because before you didn't have me.
嘿，新來的妹
Hey, new girl?
這裡每個人都是超級英雄
Everybody in this room is about that superhero life.
我直接問，這段時間妳在哪裡？
And if you don't mind my asking, where the hell have you been all this time?
宇宙中還有其他許多星球
There are a lot of other planets in the universe.
可惜它們沒有你們
And unfortunately, they didn't have you guys.
這個我喜歡
I like this one.
我們去找那個王八蛋
Let's go get this son of a bitch.
復仇者聯盟：終局之戰
好
Okay.
這裡誰沒上過太空？
Who here hasn't been to space?
幹嘛？
Why?
最好別吐在我船上
You better not throw up on my ship.
接近跳躍點，三…
Approaching jump in three...
二，一
two, one.
我去前面偵察情況
I'll head down for recon.
會成功的，史帝夫
This is gonna work, Steve.
我知道
I know it will.
否則我也束手無策了
'Cause I don't know what I'm gonna do if it doesn't.
沒衛星，沒船艦，沒軍隊
No satellites. No ships. No armies.
沒有任何地面防禦機制
No ground defenses of any kind.
只有他
It's just him.
那就夠了
And that's enough.
糟糕
Oh, no.
它們在哪裡？
Where are they?
回答問題
Answer the question.
宇宙需要修正
The universe required correction.
修正後，寶石就沒有用途
After that, the stones served no purpose...
只是誘惑
beyond temptation.
你謀殺了數十億人
You murdered trillions!
你們應該心懷感激
You should be grateful.
寶石在哪裡？
Where are the stones?
灰飛煙滅
Gone.
縮小成原子
Reduced to atoms.
兩天前你才用過它們
You used them two days ago!
我用寶石來摧毀寶石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
差點害我沒命
It nearly killed me.
但任務完成了
But the work is done.
總是會完成的
It always will be.
我是無可匹敵的
I am inevitable.
我們徹底搜索這裡，他一定在說謊
We have to tear this place apart. He has to be lying!
我父親有很多面向
My father is many things.
卻不會說謊
A liar is not one of them.
謝謝妳，女兒
Ah. Thank you, daughter.
或許我對妳太嚴厲了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
什麼？
What?
你做了什麼？
What did you do?
這次我對準了頭
I went for the head.
（五年後）
所以…
So......I, uh,
（他們不在了，我們何去何從？）
前幾天我有約會
went on a date the other day.
五年來頭一遭
It's the first time in five years.
我坐在那裡吃晚餐
You know? I'm sitting there at dinner.
根本不知道該聊什麼
I didn't even know what to talk about.
結果你們聊什麼？
What did you talk about?
老掉牙的話題…今非昔比
Eh, same old crap. You know, how things have changed.
我的工作，他的工作
My job, his job.
我們多懷念大都會隊
How much we miss the Mets.
接著兩人靜了下來
And then things got quiet...
上沙拉時他哭了出來
then he cried as they were serving the salads.
你呢？
What about you?
我在上甜點前飆淚
I cried just before dessert.
我明天還會見他，所以…
But I'm seeing him again tomorrow, so...
那很棒
That's great.
踏出第一步最難
You did the hardest part. You took the jump.
你不知道結果如何
You didn't know where you were gonna come down.
我們就是得踏出那些小小的步伐
And that's it. That's those little brave baby steps we gotta take...
努力再認真生活，尋找目標
to try and become whole again, try and find purpose.
1945年我遇見摯愛後，立刻被冷凍
I went in the ice in '45, right after I met the love of my life.
70年後才醒來
Woke up 70 years later.
日子總得過下去
You gotta move on.
就是得過下去
Gotta move on.
世界掌握在我們手中
The world is in our hands.
交到了我們手上，各位
It's left to us, guys.
我們必須善加利用
And we gotta do something with it.
否則…
Otherwise...
薩諾斯該殺光我們才對
Thanos should've killed all of us.
（舊金山）
（任你放自助倉庫）
搞什麼？
What the hell?
荷普？
Hope?
（保全）
（救命！）
（失蹤）
小朋友！
Kid!
喂，小朋友
Hey, kid!
這裡發生什麼事？
What the hell happened here?
（消逝者）
天啊
Oh, my God!
拜託
Oh, please!
拜託…
Please, please!
不…
No, no, no. No.
不
No.
抱歉
Excuse me. Sorry.
凱西，不
Oh, Cassie, no.
不…
No, no, no.
不
No, no.
拜託…不要有凱西
Please, please, please. No, Cassie.
（史考特朗恩）
什麼？
What?
凱西？
Cassie?
爸
Dad?
妳長這麼大了
You're so big!
（管制區，請勿進入）
我們登上丹佛斯發現的可疑戰艦
Yeah. We boarded that highly-suspect warship Danvers pinged.
那是艘髒亂不堪的垃圾船
It was an infectious garbage scow.
感謝提供珍貴情報
So, thanks for the hot tip.
你們比較接近嘛
Well, you were closer.
現在我們渾身垃圾味
Yeah. And now we smell like garbage.
有那些震動的讀數嗎？
You get a reading on those tremors?
那是非洲板塊底下的輕微隱沒作用
'Twas a mild subduction under the African plate.
有影像嗎？如何處理？
Do we have a visual? How are we handling it?
小娜
Nat.
那是海底的地震
It's an earthquake under the ocean.
不需要處理
We handle it by not handling it.
卡蘿，下個月妳會來嗎？
Carol, are we seeing you here next month?
-應該不會 -妳又要去剪頭髮嗎？
Not likely. What? You gonna get another haircut?
聽好，毛毛臉
Listen, fur face.
我負責的區域非常大
I'm covering a lot of territory.
其他地方都跟地球發生同樣的情形
The things that are happening on Earth are happening everywhere.
幾千顆星球
On thousands of planets.
好啦，有道理
All right, all right. That's a good point.
你們應該很久都見不到我
That's a good point. So, you might not see me for a long time.
好吧
All right. Uh, well...
這個頻道隨時暢通
This channel's always active.
只要出了問題
So, if anything goes sideways...
有人無故製造麻煩
anyone's making trouble where they shouldn't...
請通知我
comes through me.
好
Okay.
好吧
All right.
祝你好運
Good luck.
你在哪？
Where are you?
墨西哥
Mexico.
聯邦人員發現一個滿是屍體的房間
The Federales found a room full of bodies.
看來是販毒集團
Looks like a bunch of cartel guys...
連開槍的機會都沒有
never even had a chance to get their guns off.
應該是敵對幫派幹的
It's probably a rival gang.
並不是
Except it isn't.
絕對是巴頓
It's definitely Barton.
他在這裡的所作所為
What he's done here...
過去幾年來幹的好事
what he's been doing for the last few years...
他造成的後果…
I mean, the scene that he left...
其實我並不是那麼想找到他
I gotta tell you, there's a part of me that doesn't even wanna find him.
你能發現他接下來的去處嗎？
Will you find out where he's going next?
小娜？
Nat?
求求你
Please?
好吧
Okay.
我想幫妳煮晚餐
You know, I'd offer to cook you dinner...
不過妳已經夠慘了
but you seem pretty miserable already.
你來洗衣服嗎？
You here to do your laundry?
還有看朋友
And to see a friend.
你朋友明明好得很
Clearly, your friend is fine.
我過橋時看到一群鯨魚
You know, I saw a pod of whales when I was coming over the bridge.
-哈德遜河？ -船變少了…
- In the Hudson? - There's fewer ships...
水變乾淨了
cleaner water.
如果你想叫我看開點
You know, if you're about to tell me to look on the bright side...
我就用花生醬三明治丟你的頭
Um... I'm about to hit you in the head with a peanut butter sandwich.
抱歉
Hmm. Sorry.
老毛病
Force of habit.
我不斷告訴別人應該放下過去
You know, I keep telling everybody they should move on...
成長
and grow.
有的人可以
Some do.
我們辦不到
But not us.
如果我放下過去，誰來扛？
If I move on, who does this?
也許不需要有人扛
Maybe it doesn't need to be done.
從前我一無所有
I used to have nothing.
後來有了這個
And then I got this.
這個任務
This job.
這個家庭
This family.
我因此變得更好
And I was better because of it.
即使他們走了
And even though they're gone...
我還是想變得更好
I'm still trying to be better.
我們都應該好好過日子
I think we both need to get a life.
你先
You first.
嗨，有人在嗎？
Oh, hi, hi! Uh, is anyone home?
我是史考特朗恩
This is, uh, Scott Lang.
我們幾年前在德國的機場
We met a few years ago at the airport...
見過面
in Germany?
我變成巨人，戴著頭盔
I was the guy that got really big. I had a mask on.
-你們認不出我 -這是舊訊息嗎？
- You wouldn't recognize me. - Is this an old message?
蟻人，我知道你們曉得
Ant-Man? I know you know that.
-他在前門 -我真的需要跟你們談
It's the front gate. I really need to talk to you guys.
史考特
Scott.
你還好嗎？
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
你們念過量子物理學嗎？
Have either of you guys ever studied quantum physics?
只拿來聊天打屁
Only to make conversation.
好
All right, so...
五年前，就在…
five years ago, right before...
薩諾斯之前
Thanos...
我到了量子領域裡
I was in a place called the quantum realm.
量子領域自成一個微型宇宙
The quantum realm is like its own microscopic universe.
你必須變得極小才能進去
To get in there, you have to be incredibly small.
荷普，她是我的…
Hope. She's my, um...
她是我的…
She was my...
她應該讓我出去
She was supposed to pull me out.
後來發生了薩諾斯事件
And then Thanos happened...
我因而困在裡面
and I got stuck in there.
很遺憾，那五年想必很漫長
I'm sorry, that must have been a very long five years.
重點就在這裡
Yeah, but that's just it.
並不是
It wasn't.
對我來說只是五小時
For me, it was five hours.
量子領域毫無規則可言
See, the rules of the quantum realm aren't like they are up here.
一切都無法預測
Everything is unpredictable.
那是誰的三明治？
Is that anybody's sandwich?
我餓扁了
I'm starving.
史考特
Scott.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
所以…
So...
我想說的是…
what I'm saying is...
量子領域裡的時間不一樣
time works differently in the quantum realm.
唯一的問題是我們在裡面找不到方向
The only problem is right now we don't have a way to navigate it.
要是可以呢？
But what if we did?
我忍不住想，要是我們能控制混亂局面
I can't stop thinking about it. What if we could somehow control the chaos...
在裡面找到方向呢？
and we could navigate it?
要是有辦法…
What if there was a way...
在某個時間點進入量子領域
that we could enter the quantum realm at a certain point in time...
又在另一個時間點離開量子領域呢？
but then exit the quantum realm at another point in time?
譬如…
Like...
-譬如薩諾斯事件之前 -等等
- Like before Thanos. - Wait.
你說的是時間機器嗎？
Are you talking about a time machine?
當然不是，不是時間機器
No. No, of course not. No, not a time machine.
這比較像…
This is more like a...
對，像時間機器
Yeah. Like a time machine.
我知道很誇張，很誇張
I know, it's crazy. It's crazy.
但我忍不住一直想，應該…
But I can't stop thinking about it. There's gotta be...
有辦法
some way...
-太誇張了 -史考特
- It's crazy. - Scott.
我會收到浣熊寄來的電郵
I get emails from a raccoon...
已經沒什麼叫太誇張了
so nothing sounds crazy anymore.
那我們必須找誰談？
So, who do we talk to about this?
吃飯了
Chow time!
小摩
Maguna.
摩根史塔克，想吃午餐嗎？
Morgan H. Stark, you want some lunch?
解釋午餐，不然死翹翹 -好啦
Define "lunch" or be disintegrated. - Okay.
妳不應該戴這個
You should not be wearing that, okay?
這是我做給媽媽的週年紀念禮物
That is part of a special anniversary gift I'm making for Mom.
拿起來，想吃午餐嗎？
There you go. You thinking about lunch?
我弄蟋蟀配生菜給妳吃
I can give you a handful of crickets on a bed of lettuce.
-不要 -那是妳想吃的啊
- No. - That's what you want.
妳怎麼發現這個的？
How did you find this?
-車庫 -真的嗎？
- Garage. - Really?
-妳去找這個嗎？ -沒有
- Were you looking for it? - No.
不過是我發現的
- I found it, though. - Hmm.
妳喜歡去車庫喔？
You like going in the garage, huh?
把拔也是
So does Daddy.
沒關係，媽不戴我買給她的東西
It's fine, actually. Mom never wears anything I buy her.
那我就…
So, I'm gonna...
不，我們知道聽起來很扯
No. We know what it sounds like.
東尼，以你的經驗，真的有可能嗎？
Tony, after everything you've seen, is anything really impossible?
量子漲落破壞普朗克尺度
Quantum fluctuation messes with the Planck scale...
接著引發德意志命題，這我們同意吧？
which then triggers the Deutsch Proposition. Can we agree on that?
謝謝
Thank you.
講白話，這表示回不了家
In layman's terms, it means you're not coming home.
-我回來了 -不對
- I did. - No.
你是意外活下來
You accidentally survived.
十億分之一的僥倖
It's a billion-to-one cosmic fluke.
現在你想…那叫什麼？
And now you wanna pull a... What do you call it?
時間攔劫？
A time heist?
對，時間攔劫，以前怎麼沒想到？
Yeah, a time heist. Of course. Why didn't we think of this before?
因為很可笑，癡人說夢
Oh, because it's laughable. Because it's a pipe dream.
無限寶石在過去，我們能回去搶過來
The stones are in the past. We could go back, we could get them.
我們一彈指就能救回所有人
We can snap our own fingers. We can bring everybody back.
或者火上加油
Or screw it up worse than he already has, right?
我認為不會
I don't believe we would.
有時好懷念這種天真的樂觀態度
Gotta say it. I sometimes miss that giddy optimism.
寄予厚望並沒有幫助
However, high hopes won't help...
如果缺少安全執行時間攔劫的具體方法
if there's no logical, tangible way for me to safely execute said time heist.
我想最可能的結果是我們集體死亡
I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.
嚴格遵守時間旅行的規則就不會
Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.
也就是不跟過去的自己對話
All right? It means no talking to our past selves...
不賭運動比賽
no betting on sporting events.
我要請你住嘴，史考特
I'm gonna stop you right there, Scott.
你意思是說你拯救宇宙的計畫
Are you seriously telling me that your plan to save the universe...
是根據《回到未來》？
is based on Back to the Future?
-是嗎？ -不是
- Is it? - No.
你害我擔心了一下，那根本狗屁不通
Good. You had me worried there. 'Cause that would be horseshit.
量子物理學不是那樣運作的
That's not how quantum physics works.
東尼
Tony.
我們必須堅定立場
We have to take a stand.
我們有，卻落得如此下場
We did stand. And yet, here we are.
我知道你得冒很大的風險
I know you got a lot on the line.
你有老婆，女兒
You got a wife, a daughter.
但我失去了一個非常重要的人
But I lost someone very important to me.
很多人也一樣
A lotta people did.
現在我們有機會把她救回來
And now, now we have a chance to bring her back...
把所有人救回來，你卻說你根本不…
to bring everyone back, and you're telling me that you won't even...
沒錯，我根本不願意
That's right, Scott. I won't even.
我不能
I can't.
媽咪叫我來救你
Mommy told me to come and save you.
很好，我得救了
Good job. I'm saved.
真希望你們是來問別的事，什麼都好
I wish you were coming here to ask me something else. Anything else.
很高興見到你們
I'm honestly happy to see you guys, I just...
-午餐準備了六人份 -東尼
Oh, look, the table's set for six.
我懂
Tony. I get it.
我替你高興，真的
And I'm happy for you. I really am.
但這是第二次機會
But this is a second chance.
我的第二次機會在這裡，隊長
I got my second chance right here, Cap.
不能冒險
Can't roll the dice on it.
不聊工作的話請留下來吃飯
If you don't talk shop, you can stay for lunch.
他怕了
Well, he's scared.
他也沒錯
He's not wrong.
那我們怎麼辦？
Yeah, but, I mean, what are we gonna do?
我們需要他，難道就此收手嗎？
We need him. What, are we gonna stop?
不，我想妥善規劃
No, I wanna do it right.
我們需要一個非常聰明的人
We're gonna need a really big brain.
比他還聰明？
Bigger than his?
好像只有我在吃，嚐嚐看嘛
Come on, I feel like I'm the only one eating here.
吃點蛋
Try some of that. Have some eggs.
我搞糊塗了
I'm so confused.
這年頭是很讓人困惑
These are confusing times.
我不是那意思
Right, no, no. That's not what I meant.
我瞭，開玩笑的
Nah, I get it. I'm kidding!
我知道很扯
I know, it's crazy.
我竟然穿衣服
I'm wearing shirts now.
對啊，怎麼會？為什麼？
Yeah. What? How? Why?
五年前，我們吃了敗仗
Five years ago, we got our asses beat.
只是我更慘
Except it was worse for me...
我輸了兩次
'cause I lost twice.
首先浩克輸了，班納又輸
First, Hulk lost, then Banner lost...
然後我們全都輸了
and then, we all lost.
沒人怪你，布魯斯
No one blamed you, Bruce.
我怪我自己
I did.
多年來我把浩克當成一種病
For years, I've been treating the Hulk like he's some kind
想去之而後快
of disease... something to get rid of.
後來我開始將他視為解藥
But then, I start looking at him as the cure.
在伽瑪實驗室研究了18個月
Eighteen months in the gamma lab.
將智慧與體力結合起來
I put the brains and the brawn together...
現在看看我
and now, look at me.
頭腦和四肢同樣發達
Best of both worlds.
-對不起，浩克先生？ -是
- Excuse me, Mr. Hulk? - Yes.
我們能跟你合照嗎？
Can we get a photo?
沒問題，小朋友
100%, little person.
過來…幫我們拍？
Come on, step on up. Do you mind?
-好啊 -謝謝
- Oh, yeah, yeah. - Thanks.
說七
Say "green."
-七 -七
- Green. - Green.
拍到了嗎？
Did you get that?
很好看
That's a good one.
想跟我合照嗎？我是蟻人
Did you want to grab one with me? I'm Ant-Man.
他們是浩克粉絲，不認識蟻人
They're Hulk fans. They don't know Ant-Man.
沒人認識我
Nobody does.
-他要你跟他合照 -我不想拍
- No, he wants you to take a picture with him. - I don't want a picture.
小心怪叔叔
Stranger danger.
他竟然拒絕
Yeah, look, he's even saying no, he doesn't.
-我懂了，我也不想拍 -別這樣
I get it. I don't want it, either.
我不想跟他們合照
But come on. The kid... I don't want a picture with them.
-他會很難過 -抱歉
- He's gonna feel bad. - Sorry.
他們很樂意合照
They're happy to do it. They said they'll do it.
-我不想拍 -我們可以
- I don't want to do it. - We can do it.
-你不爽了 -手機拿去
- No, you feel bad. - Take the goddamn phone.
好
Okay.
-謝謝你，浩克先生 -很棒，謝謝你們
Thank you, Mr. Hulk. No, it was great, kids. Thank you very much.
浩克萬歲
Hulk out!
布魯斯
Bruce.
帥
Dab.
-布魯斯 -要聽媽媽的話
- Bruce. - Listen to your mom.
她懂比較多
She knows better.
關於我們說的事
About what we were saying.
對
Right.
靠時間旅行來逆轉？
The whole time travel do-over?
那超出我的專業領域
Eh, guys, it's outside of my area of expertise.
你成功轉型了啊
Well, you pulled this off.
以前這也是不可能的任務
I remember a time when that seemed pretty impossible, too.
我有一點靈感，想看看是否正確
I've got a mild inspiration. I'd like to see if it checks out.
睡前我想做最後一次模擬
So, I'd like to run one last sim before we pack it in for the night.
這次用反轉的莫比烏斯帶形狀
This time, in the shape of a Möbius strip, inverted, please.
處理中
Processing.
給我那個粒子的特徵值
Right, give me the eigenvalue of that particle...
並考慮頻譜分解
factoring in spectral decomp.
-這需要一段時間 -請稍候
- That'll take a second. - Just a moment.
不順利的話也別擔心，我…
And don't worry if it doesn't pan out. I'm just kinda...
模型成形
Model rendered.
（模型成功）
靠！
Shit!
妳怎麼起來了，小姐？
What are you doing up, little miss?
-靠 -不能說這個字
- Shit. - Nope. We don't say that.
只有媽咪才能說
Only Mommy says that word.
她發明的，媽咪專用
She coined it. It belongs to her.
你怎麼起來了？
Why are you up?
因為我有重要的事要做
'Cause I've got some important shit going on here!
妳覺得呢？
Why do you think?
不，我在想事情…
No, I got something on my mind.
你在想果汁冰棒嗎？
I got something on my mind. Was it juice pops?
當然
Sure was.
妳勒索我
That's extortion. That's a word.
妳要哪一種？
What kind you want?
英雄所見略同
Great minds think alike.
果汁冰棒就是…
Juice pops exactly...
我腦袋在想的
was on my mind.
吃完了嗎？
You done? Yeah?
吃完了
Now you are.
擦擦
Here. Wipe.
好，躺下去
Good. That face goes there.
說故事給我聽
Tell me a story.
故事
A story.
很久以前，小摩上床睡覺，完
Once upon a time, Maguna went to bed. The end.
好爛的故事
That is a horrible story.
這是妳最喜歡的故事
Come on, that's your favourite story.
愛妳喔
Love you tons.
我愛你三千次
I love you 3,000.
哇
Wow.
三千次，超多的
3,000. That's crazy.
睡覺，不然賣掉妳的玩具
Go to bed or I'll sell all your toys.
晚安
Night night.
這不是比賽
Not that it's a competition...
不過她愛我三千次
but she loves me 3,000.
是喔？
Does she, now?
妳只有六百到九百次
You were somewhere in the low 6 to 900 range.
在看什麼？
Whatcha reading?
製作堆肥的書
Just a book on composting.
堆肥有什麼新發展？
What's new with composting?
-有趣的科學… -我想通了
- Interesting science... - I figured it out.
順便說一聲
By the way.
我們講的是同一件事…
And, you know, just so we're talking about the same thing...
時間旅行
Time travel.
什麼？
What?
哇
Wow.
好驚人
That's amazing...
也好可怕
and terrifying.
沒錯
That's right.
我們真的很幸運
We got really lucky.
嗯
Yeah.
我知道
I know.
很多人沒這麼好運
A lot of people didn't.
對，我救不了所有人
Nope. And I can't help everybody.
感覺好像你可以
Sorta seems like you can.
我停止的話就不能
Not if I stop.
我能馬上煞車，停止
I can put a pin in it right now and stop.
東尼
Tony...
設法阻止你
trying to get you to stop...
是我這輩子最大的敗筆之一
has been one of the few failures of my entire life.
我有種感覺
Something tells me...
我應該把它鎖進箱子，丟到湖底
I should put it in a lockbox and drop it to the bottom of the lake...
上床睡覺
and go to bed.
但你睡得著嗎？
But would you be able to rest?
開始，時間旅行第一次測試
Okay, here we go. Time travel test number one.
史考特，發動…
Scott, fire up...
廂型車
the, uh, van thing.
斷路器準備
Breakers are set.
緊急發電機就緒
Emergency generators are on standby.
要是斷電，我可不想在50年代失去奈米哥
Good, because if we blow the grid, I don't want to lose, uh, Tiny here in the 1950s.
你說什麼？
- Excuse me?
他開玩笑的
- He's kidding.
你不能說這種話
You can't say things like that.
冷笑話
It was a bad joke.
你開玩笑的吧？
You were kidding, right?
我不知道，這可是時間旅行
I have no idea. We're talking about time travel here.
可能全是笑話，也可能都不是
Either it's all a joke, or none of it is.
搞定了
We're good!
戴上頭盔
Get your helmet on.
史考特，我送你回到一週前
Scott, I'm gonna send you back a week...
讓你待一小時，十秒後帶你回來
let you walk around for an hour, then bring you back in 10 seconds.
有道理嗎？
Make sense?
十分清楚
Perfectly not confusing.
祝你好運，史考特，你沒問題的
Good luck, Scott. You got this.
對，我沒問題，美國隊長…
You're right. I do, Captain America.
倒數三秒
On a count of three...
三，二，一
Three, two, one.
大夥
Uh... Guys?
感覺不對勁
This doesn't feel right.
怎麼了？
What is this?
-怎麼搞的？ -他是誰？
- What's going on? - Who is that?
-等等 -那是史考特嗎？
- Hold on. - Is that Scott?
我是史考特
Yes, it's Scott.
-怎麼了，布魯斯？ -我的背！
- What's going on, Bruce? - Oh, my back!
-怎麼搞的？ -等一下
- What is this? - Hold on a second.
-給我一點空間 -好
Could I get a little space here? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-你能帶他回來嗎？ -正在想辦法
Can you bring him back? I'm working on it.
一個嬰兒
It's a baby.
-是史考特 -變成嬰兒
- It's Scott. - As a baby.
-他會長大 -帶史考特回來
- He'll grow. - Bring Scott back.
我說關掉就關掉
When I say kill the power, kill the power.
天啊
Oh, my God.
關掉
And... kill it!
有人尿在我褲子上
Somebody peed my pants.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
不知是嬰兒期的我還是老年的我
But I don't know if it was baby me or old me.
或者現在的我
Or just me me.
時間旅行
Time travel!
怎樣？
What?
我覺得非常成功
I see this as an absolute win.
幹嘛苦瓜臉？
Why the long face?
我猜，他變成嬰兒
Let me guess, he turned into a baby.
是有那麼一回事，你來幹嘛？
Among other things, yeah. What are you doing here?
這是EPR弔詭
It's the EPR Paradox.
與其讓朗恩穿越時間，不如…
Instead of pushing Lang through time,
讓時間穿越朗恩
you might've wound up... pushing time through Lang.
那樣困難又危險，該有人警告你們的
It's tricky, dangerous. Somebody could have cautioned you against it.
你警告過了
You did.
是嗎？
Oh, did I?
幸好我來了
Well, thank God I'm here.
反正，我修好了
Regardless, I fixed it.
運作正常的時空GPS
A fully functioning time-space GPS.
我只要和解
I just want peace.
怨恨有害身心，我不喜歡
Turns out resentment is corrosive, and I hate it.
我也是
Me, too.
有機會拿到寶石，但先說我的優先順序
We got a shot at getting these stones, but I gotta tell you my priorities.
我希望救回失去的
Bring back what we lost, I hope, yes.
不計代價留下我發現的
Keep what I found, I have to, at all costs.
但願不必至死方休
And maybe not die trying.
那樣就好
Would be nice.
聽起來可行
Sounds like a deal.
東尼，我不知道
Tony, I don't know.
為什麼？
Why?
他為你做的
He made it for you.
我特地從垃圾堆挖出來，免得摩根當雪橇
Plus, honestly, I have to get it out of the garage before Morgan takes it sledding.
謝謝你，東尼
Thank you, Tony.
可以別聲張嗎？
Will you keep that a little quiet?
不是每個人都有
Didn't bring one for the whole team.
我們會集結整個團隊吧？
We are getting the whole team, yeah?
正在努力
We're working on that right now.
人類哥
Hey, Humie.
綠巨人呢？
Where's Big Green?
在廚房吧
The kitchen, I think.
帥呆了
That's awesome.
羅德，重新進入時小心
Rhodey, careful on re-entry.
降落區有個白癡
There's an idiot in the landing zone.
天啊
Oh, God.
你好，正常尺寸蟻人
What's up, Regular-Sized Man?
（歡迎蒞臨新阿斯嘉，請慢速行駛）
這比黃金宮殿和魔力神鎚掉漆多了
Kind of a step down from the golden palaces and the magic hammers and what not.
有點同情心
Hey, have a little compassion, pal.
他們先失去阿斯嘉，又少了一半人口
First, they lost Asgard, then half their people.
有個家就偷笑了
They're probably just happy to have a home.
你們不該來的
You shouldn't have come.
瓦爾基麗
Ah! Valkyrie!
真高興見到妳，憤怒姊
Great to see you, angry girl!
我比較喜歡你原來那兩個版本
I think I liked you better either of the other ways.
-這是火箭 -妳好嗎？
This is Rocket. How ya doing?
他不會見你們的
He won't see you.
那麼慘？
It's that bad, huh?
我們一個月只見他一次…他來補貨時
We only see him once a month
（阿斯嘉麥芽啤酒，黑啤酒）
when he comes in for "supplies."
慘到爆
It's that bad.
是啊
Yeah.
怎麼…
What the...?
有東西死在裡面
Whew! Something died in here!
哈囉？索爾
Hello? Thor!
你是來修第四台嗎？
Are you here about the cable?
電影台兩週前就不能看
The Cinemax went out two weeks ago...
體育台有雜訊
and the sports are all kinda fuzzy and whatnot.
索爾？
Thor?
兄弟們，歐買尬！
Boys! Oh, my God!
見到你們真好
Oh, my God, it's so good to see you!
過來抱抱，小痞子
Come here, cuddly little rascal.
我很好…
Yeah, no, I'm good. I'm good.
沒必要這樣
That's not necessary.
浩克，認識我朋友米克和寇格吧？
Hulk, you know my friends Miek and Korg, right?
-你們好 -嗨
- Hey, boys! - Hey, guys.
好久不見
Long time no see.
桶子裡有啤酒，無線網路儘管用
Beer's in the bucket. Feel free to log on to the Wi-Fi.
不用密碼
No password, obviously.
索爾，他回來了
Thor, he's back.
電視上那小子又叫我豬頭
That kid on the TV just called me a dickhead again.
菜鳥大師
Noobmaster.
菜鳥大師69叫我豬頭
Yeah, NoobMaster69 called me a dickhead.
你好遜
I am sick of this.
菜鳥大師，又是我，雷神索爾
Noobmaster, hey, it's Thor again. You know, the God of Thunder.
聽好，你要是不馬上登出這遊戲
Listen, bud, if you don't log off this game immediately...
我就飛去你家，闖進你躲的地下室
I am gonna fly over to your house, come down to that basement you're hiding in...
扯斷你手臂，再塞進你屁眼
rip off your arms, and shove them up your butt!
沒錯，哭給你老北聽，賤胚
Oh, that's right, yes! Go cry to your father, you little weasel.
謝謝你，索爾
Thank you, Thor.
他再煩你就告訴我
Let me know if he bothers you again, okay?
感恩，我會的
Thank you very much. I will.
你們想喝什麼嗎？
So, you guys want a drink? What are we drinking?
我有啤酒、龍舌蘭，應有盡有
I've got beer, tequila, all sorts of things.
兄弟
Buddy.
你還好嗎？
- You all right?
我很好，怎樣？
- Yes, I'm fine. Why?
我看起來不好嗎？
Why, don't I look all right?
你活像彌勒佛
You look like melted ice cream.
怎樣？過來聊天打屁嗎？
So, what's up? You just here for a hang, or what?
我們需要你幫忙
- We need your help. - Mm.
我們有機會逆轉局勢
There might be a chance we could fix everything.
修第四台嗎？
What, like the cable?
它害我抓狂好幾星期了
'Cause that's been driving me bananas for weeks.
薩諾斯
Like Thanos.
別提起這名字
Don't say that name.
這裡不准說到那個髒東西
Um, yeah, we don't actually say that name in here.
請把手拿開
Please take your hand off me.
我知道那個傢伙…
Now, I know that guy...
可能嚇到你
might scare you.
怎麼會？
Why would I be...?
我怎麼會被那傢伙嚇到？
Why would I be scared of that guy?
那傢伙是我殺的，記得嗎？
I'm the one who killed that guy, remember?
這裡有別人殺了他嗎？
Hmm. Anyone else here kill that guy?
沒有
Nope.
應該沒有
Didn't think so.
寇格，告訴大家誰砍掉薩諾斯的頭？
Korg, why don't you, uh, tell everybody who chopped Thanos' big head off?
風暴破壞者？
Um, Stormbreaker?
誰揮舞風暴破壞者？
Who was swinging Stormbreaker?
我瞭解，你很不好受
I get it. You're in a rough spot, okay?
我感同身受
I've been there myself.
想知道誰幫我走出來嗎？
And you want to know who helped me out of it?
是娜塔莎嗎？
Was it Natasha?
是你
It was you.
你幫助我
You helped me.
你怎麼不問問…
So, why don't you ask...
下面那些阿斯嘉人
the Asgardians down there...
我的幫助值多少？
how much my help is worth?
剩下的那些人
The ones that are left, anyway.
我想我們能救他們回來
I think we could bring them back.
別講了
Stop.
別講了好嗎？
Stop, okay?
你以為我在這裡自艾自憐
I know you think I'm down here wallowing in my own self-pity...
等著被人拯救
waiting to be rescued and saved...
我很好，我們很好，對不對？
but I'm fine, okay. We're fine, aren't we?
我們在這裡好得很
Oh, we're good here, mate.
不管你有什麼提議，我們沒興趣
So, whatever it is that you're offering, we're not into it.
完全不在乎
Don't care. Couldn't care less.
再見
Goodbye.
我們需要你
We need you, pal.
船上有啤酒
There's beer on the ship.
哪一種？
What kind?
（東京）
是他！他在追殺昭彥
你為什麼這麼做？
我們從來沒招惹過你
你們活了下來
地球一半生物卻沒有
他們碰上薩諾斯
你們碰上我
你們不能再傷人了
我們傷人？
你瘋了
等等，救我！
我什麼都能給你
你要什麼？
我要的，你沒辦法給
What I want you can't give me.
妳不該來這裡
You shouldn't be here.
你也不應該
Neither should you.
我有任務在身
I've got a job to do.
這就是你的任務嗎？
Is that what you're calling this?
殺死這些人也不能讓你家人回來
Killing all these people isn't gonna bring your family back.
我們有所發現
We found something.
說不定是個機會
A chance, maybe.
不要
Don't.
不要什麼？
Don't what?
不要給我希望
Don't give me hope.
抱歉我不能早點給你
I'm sorry I couldn't give it to you sooner.
你往左偏了
You're drifting left.
直走，酒鬼
One side there, Lebowski.
火焰，你好嗎？
Ratchet, how's it going?
是火箭
It's Rocket.
放輕鬆，你只在地球上是天才
Take it easy. You're only a genius on Earth, pal.
時間旅行裝，不錯嘛
Time travel suit, not bad.
喂…輕一點…
Hey, hey, hey! Easy! Easy!
我非常小心
I'm being very careful.
才怪，你非常浩克
No, you're being very Hulky.
我非常小心
I'm being careful.
這些是皮姆粒子
These are Pym Particles, all right?
自從漢克皮姆消失後，只剩這個
And ever since Hank Pym got snapped out of existence, this is it.
我們只有這個，再也做不出來了
This is what we have. We're not making any more.
-史考特，冷靜點 -抱歉
- Scott, calm down. - Sorry.
我們只夠一趟來回
We've got enough for one round-trip each. That's it.
不能重來
No do-overs.
再加兩次測試
Plus two test runs.
一次測試
One test run.
好，我還沒準備好
All right. I'm not ready for this.
我可以試試
I'm game.
讓我來
I'll do it.
克林特，你會因時間轉移而感到混亂
Clint, now you're gonna feel a little discombobulated from the chronoshift.
-別擔心 -等等，我先問一件事
Don't worry about that. Wait a second. Let me ask you something.
如果我們能回到過去
If we can do this, you know...
何不乾脆去找薩諾斯寶寶？
go back in time, why don't we just find baby Thanos?
就是…
You know, and...
-首先，那樣很恐怖 -他是薩諾斯啊
First of all, that's horrible. It's Thanos.
第二，時間不是那樣運作的
And secondly, time doesn't work that way.
改變時間不會改變未來
Changing the past doesn't change the future.
我們回去，比薩諾斯先拿到寶石
Look, we go back, we get the stones before Thanos gets them...
薩諾斯沒有寶石，問題解決
Thanos doesn't have the stones. Problem solved.
-沒錯 -不是那樣子
- Bingo. - That's not how it works.
-我聽到的是 -誰，誰告訴你的？
Well, that's what I heard. Wait, but who? Who told you that?
"星際爭霸戰"、"魔鬼終結者"、"時空特警"
Star Trek, Terminator, Timecop...
-"兩世奇人" -"時空怪客"
- Time After Time. - Quantum Leap.
-"時間的皺摺"、"似曾相識" -"扭轉時光機"
Wrinkle in Time, Somewhere in Time.
"扭轉時光機"﹑"阿比阿弟的冒險"
Hot Tub Time Machine. Hot Tub Time Machine.
就是任何講時間旅行的電影
Bill and Ted's Excellent Adventure. Basically, any movie that deals with time travel.
"終極警探"…那部不是
Die Hard. No, that's not one.
這是常識
This is known.
我不知道為何大家都信，那不正確
I don't know why everyone believes that, but that isn't true.
想想看，如果旅行到過去
Think about it. If you travel to the past...
那個過去就成了你的未來
that past becomes your future...
你以前的現在就成為過去
and your former present becomes the past...
無法被新的未來改變
which can't now be changed by your new future.
沒錯
Exactly.
所以"回到未來"都在鬼扯？
So Back to the Future is a bunch of bullshit?
好，克林特
All right, Clint.
倒數三，二…
We're going in three, two...
一
one.
（量子目標）
庫柏
Cooper?
我的耳機呢？
Where are my headphones?
萊拉？
Lila?
-我沒拿 -萊拉？
- I never had them. - Lila?
你昨天拿去了
Yeah, you had them yesterday!
萊拉…
Lila! Lila!
爸？
Yeah, Dad?
Dad?
萊拉
Lila!
嘿…看著我
Hey. Hey, look at me.
你還好嗎？
You okay?
還好
Yeah. Yeah.
成功了
It worked.
（時間攔劫，腦力激盪時間）
（宇宙魔方，空間寶石）
所以方法可行
Okay, so the how works.
現在要找出時間和地點
Now, we gotta figure out the when and the where.
在場幾乎每個人都曾經…
Almost everyone in this room has had an encounter...
與至少一顆無限寶石交手過
with at least one of the six Infinity Stones.
也可以把交手二字
Or substitute the word "encounter"...
改成差點被無限寶石殺死
for "damn near been killed" by one of the six Infinity Stones.
我沒有
Well, I haven't...
我根本不知道你們在說什麼
but I don't even know what the hell you're all talking about.
無論如何，皮姆粒子只夠一趟來回使用
Regardless, we only have enough Pym Particles for one round-trip each.
這些寶石在歷史上許多地方出現過
And these stones have been in a lot of different places throughout history.
我們的歷史
Our history.
容易前往的時間點並不多
So, not a lot of convenient spots to just drop in, yeah?
所以我們必須挑選目標
Which means we have to pick our targets.
正確
Correct.
那就從以太寶石開始
So, let's start with the Aether.
索爾，你知道什麼？
Thor, what do you know?
他在睡覺嗎？
Is he asleep?
不，我確定他死了
No, no. I'm pretty sure he's dead.
（目標：現實寶石）
從哪裡開始講？
Uh, where to start? Um...
首先，以太寶石不是寶石
The Aether, firstly, is not a stone.
以前有人叫它寶石
Someone called it a stone before.
它應該是一坨憤怒的爛泥
Um, it's more of an angry sludge sort of a thing...
有人必須更正，別再那樣說
so someone's gonna need to amend that and stop saying that.
不過以太有個有趣的故事…
Here's an interesting story, though, about the Aether.
多年前，我祖父…
My grandfather, many years ago...
不得不藏起寶石，避開黑暗精靈
had to hide the stone from the Dark Elves.
他們很恐怖
Ooh. Scary beings.
珍其實…
So, Jane, actually...
她在這裡
Oh, there she is.
珍是我的舊情人
Yeah, so Jane was an old flame of mine.
有一次她的手卡在石頭裡
You know, she stuck her hand inside a rock this one time...
後來以太寶石卡在她體內
and then the Aether stuck itself inside her...
她就病得非常嚴重
and she became very, very sick.
我不得不帶她去阿斯嘉，我老家
And so I had to take her to Asgard, which is where I'm from...
想辦法治療她
and we had to try and fix her.
當時我們在交往
We were dating at the time, you see...
我介紹她給我母親
and I got to introduce her to my mother...
我媽死了…
who's dead and, um...
珍和我已經分手了
Oh, you know, Jane and I aren't even dating anymore, so...
男女分分合合
Yes, these things happen, though. You know?
沒什麼永恆，唯一…
Nothing lasts forever. The only thing that...
-過來坐下吧 -我還沒講完
- Why don't you come sit down? - I'm not done yet.
人生唯一恆久的東西就是無常
The only thing that is permanent in life is impermanence.
棒呆了，想吃蛋嗎？早餐？
Awesome. Eggs? Breakfast?
不，我要一杯血腥瑪莉
No. I'd like a Bloody Mary.
奎爾說他從莫拉格偷走力量寶石
Quill said he stole the Power Stone from Morag.
（目標：力量寶石）
-那是一個人嗎？ -不，莫拉格是星球
- Is that a person? - No, Morag's a planet.
奎爾才是人
Quill was a person.
星球？在外太空？
Like a planet? Like in outer space?
看，好像一隻開心的小狗狗
Oh, look. It's like a little puppy, all happy and everything.
想上太空嗎？想上太空嗎，小狗狗？
Do you wanna go to space? You wanna go to space, puppy?
我帶你上太空
I'll take you to space.
（目標：靈魂寶石）
薩諾斯在佛米爾發現靈魂寶石
Thanos found the Soul Stone on Vormir.
佛米爾是什麼？
What is Vormir?
死亡之地
A dominion of death...
位於宇宙的中心
at the very center of celestial existence.
薩諾斯謀殺我姊的地方
It's where Thanos murdered my sister.
我不去
Not it.
（目標：時間寶石）
-時間寶石男 -奇異博士
- That Time Stone guy. - Doctor Strange.
他是哪種博士？
Yeah, what kind of doctor was he?
耳鼻喉科醫生兼魔術師
Ear-nose-throat meets rabbit-from-hat.
他在格林威治村的家挺漂亮的
Nice place in the Village, though.
在蘇利文街？
Yeah, on Sullivan Street?
布利克街
Mm... Bleecker Street.
他住紐約？
Wait, he lived in New York?
-不，多倫多 -布利克和蘇利文街口
No, he lived in Toronto. Uh, yeah, on Bleecker and Sullivan.
-妳有認真聽嗎？ -各位
Have you been listening to anything? Guys.
如果挑對年份，紐約會有三顆寶石
If you pick the right year, there are three stones in New York.
真的假的
Shut the front door.
（紐約，阿斯嘉，莫拉格／佛米爾）
好，計畫成形
All right. We have a plan.
六顆寶石，三個團隊，一次機會
Six stones, three teams, one shot.
五年前我們輸了
Five years ago, we lost.
一敗塗地
All of us.
我們失去朋友
We lost friends.
失去家人
We lost family.
失去部分的自我
We lost a part of ourselves.
如今我們有機會扭轉乾坤
Today, we have a chance to take it all back.
你們知道自己的團隊和任務
You know your teams. You know your missions.
奪回寶石，救他們回來
Get the stones. Get them back.
來回一趟
One round-trip each.
不准出錯
No mistakes...
不能重來
no do-overs.
我們大多會去我們熟悉的地方
Most of us are going somewhere we know.
那不表示我們能預測會遇到什麼
That doesn't mean we should know what to expect.
萬事小心
Be careful.
彼此照應
Look out for each other.
這是我們畢生最大的戰役
This is the fight of our lives...
只許成功
and we're gonna win.
不計代價
Whatever it takes.
祝好運
Good luck.
他挺會講的
He's pretty good at that.
-對啊 -好
- Right? - All right.
你們聽到了，開始輸入，綠巨人
You heard the man. Stroke those keys, Jolly Green.
追蹤器就緒
Trackers engaged.
你保證把它完整帶回來？
You promise to bring that back in one piece, right?
對啦…
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
好，我會盡力
Okay, I'll do my best.
這種保證真沒說服力
As promises go, that was pretty lame.
待會見
See ya in a minute.
（紐約，2012年）
我們各有任務在身
All right, we all have our assignments.
兩顆寶石在上城，一顆在下城
Two stones uptown, one stone down.
保持低調，注意時間
Stay low. Keep an eye on the clock.
也許過程中砸爛幾樣東西
Maybe smash a few things along the way.
我覺得太超過，不過隨便啦
I think it's gratuitous, but whatever.
走那邊要小心，地板剛打過蠟
I'd be careful going that way. We just had the floors waxed.
我找奇異博士
Yeah, I'm looking for Doctor Strange.
你早來了五年
You're about five years too early.
史蒂芬史傳奇正在20條街以外開刀
Stephen Strange is currently performing surgery about 20 blocks that way.
找他有什麼事？
What do you want from him?
要那個東西
That, actually.
恐怕不行
Ah! I'm afraid not.
抱歉，我不是在問妳
Sorry, but I wasn't asking.
最好別這麼做
You don't want to do this.
對，但我需要那寶石
Ah, you're right, I don't. But I need that stone...
沒時間跟妳辯
and I don't have time to debate it.
我們重新來過吧？
Let's start over, shall we?
（阿斯嘉，2013年）
給妳的，珍夫人
For you, Lady Jane.
你們有搭長褲的嗎？
Um, so you have anything with pants?
長褲？
Pants?
算了，這件可以，謝謝
Never mind. These will be fine. Thank you.
-是，夫人 -那是珍
- Yes, milady. - Oh, there's Jane.
好
All right.
這樣吧，肥仔
Here's the deal, tubby.
你去引誘她，我用這個捅她
You're gonna charm her, and I'm gonna poke her with this thing...
搶走現實寶石就閃人
and extract the Reality Stone, and get gone lickety-split.
我馬上回來，酒窖就在下面
I'll be right back, okay? The wine cellar is just down here.
家父以前有一大桶阿孔麥芽啤酒
My father used to have this huge barrel of Aakonian ale.
我去廚房找外帶杯
I'll see if the scullery has a couple of to-go cups.
喂！你喝得不夠茫嗎？
Hey. Hey! Aren't you drunk enough already?
-請妳送湯給洛基 -是，夫人
If you could send Loki some soup. Yes, milady.
請圖書館員拿些天文學的書
And ask our librarians to pull some volumes from the astronomy shelf.
那個美魔女是誰？
Who's the fancy broad?
那是我母親
That's my mother.
她今天去世
She dies today.
那是今天？
Oh, that is today?
我做不到…
I can't do this. I can't do this.
我不該在這裡，我不該來
I shouldn't be here. I shouldn't have come.
這是個餿主意
It's a bad idea!
-過來 -不…
- Come here. - No, no, no.
我恐慌發作了
I think I'm having a panic attack.
-過來這裡 -我不該來的，這樣不對
Come here. Right here. I shouldn't be here. This is bad.
難道只有你失去親友嗎？
You think you're the only one who lost people?
你以為我們在這裡做什麼？
What do you think we're doing here?
我失去我僅有的家人
I lost the only family I ever had.
奎爾、格魯特、德克斯、長觸角的妞
Quill, Groot, Drax, the chick with the antenna...
全都消失了
all gone.
我知道你想你媽
I get you miss your mom...
可是她走了
but she's gone.
真的走了
Really gone.
有很多人只是消失
And there are plenty of people who are only kind of gone...
你能救他們
and you can help them.
所以請你刷掉鬍鬚上的碎屑
So, is it too much to ask that you brush the crumbs out of your beard...
去跟那個褲子姊喇低賽
make schmoopy talk to Pretty Pants...
趁她不注意時拿走無限寶石
and when she's not looking, suck out the Infinity Stone...
救我家人回來，行嗎？
and help me get my family back?
好
Okay.
你哭了？
Are you crying?
哪有
No.
對啦
Yes.
我快淚崩了
I feel like I'm losing it.
振作一點
Get it together!
你做得到
You can do this.
好不好？
All right?
對，我可以
Yes, I can.
很好
Good.
我做得到…
I can do this. I can do this.
我做不到
I can't do this.
撩妹王，她落單，機會來了
All right, heartbreaker, she's alone.
索爾？
This is our shot. Thor? Thor!
（莫拉格星，2014年）
降落，藍臉妹
All right, bring it down, Blue.
降在線上，下去
Right on that line. That's it. Down, down.
可以快點嗎？
Hey, can we hurry it up?
動作快，我們趕時間
Guys, chop-chop. Come on. We're on the clock.
這樣嗆聲很有幫助喔
All that is really helpful.
-保重 -好
- Take care, okay? - Yeah.
把寶石拿回來，別玩瘋了
Get that stone and come back. No messing around.
-嘿 -我們可以的
- Hey. - We got this.
-完成任務 -是
- Let's get it done. - Yes, sir.
回頭見
I'll see you back.
記得互相照應
You guys watch each other's six.
好
Yeah.
佛米爾星的座標已儲存
Coordinates for Vormir are laid in.
他們只要別起衝突就好
All they have to do is not fall out.
布達佩斯是好久以前的事了
We're a long way from Budapest.
好
Okay, so, uh...
我們等奎爾出現
we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
他就會帶我們去找力量寶石，對吧？
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我們找掩護
Let's take cover.
2014年不只有我們在找寶石
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
等一下，妳在說什麼？
Wait a minute. What are you talking about right now?
還有誰在找這些寶石？
Who else is looking for these stones?
我父親
My father...
我姊
my sister...
和我
and me.
妳？
And you?
妳現在在哪裡？
Where are you right now?
別客氣
You're welcome.
我沒請妳幫忙
I didn't ask for your help.
但妳一向需要幫忙
And yet, you always need it.
起來，父親要我們回船上
Get up. Father wants us back on the ship.
為什麼？
Why?
他發現了一顆無限寶石
He's found an Infinity Stone.
在哪裡？
Where?
一個叫莫拉格的星球
On a planet called Morag.
父親的計畫終於啟動了
Father's plan is finally in motion.
才一顆寶石而已，涅布拉
One stone isn't six, Nebula.
總是個開始
It's a start.
如果他全部拿到手…
If he gets all of them...
羅南發現力量寶石位置，我派妳們去他船上
Ronan's located the Power Stone. I'm dispatching you to his ship.
他會不高興
He won't like that.
那他就別想活了
His alternative is death.
羅南的執迷
Ronan's obsession...
影響了他的判斷力
clouds his judgment.
我們不會讓你失望，父親
We will not fail you, Father.
妳們不會
No, you won't.
我發誓…
I swear...
我會讓你感到驕傲
I will make you proud.
我們等奎爾出現
...we just wait around for this Quill guy to show up...
他會帶我們去找力量寶石，對吧？
and then he leads us to the Power Stone, is that it?
我們找掩護
Let's take cover.
2014年不只有我們在找寶石
We're not the only ones in 2014 looking for the stones.
那是誰？
Who was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我頭痛欲裂，不知道
My head is splitting. I don't know.
她的突觸硬碟大概在打鬥時受損
Her synaptic drive was probably damaged in battle.
Shh.
帶她到我船上
Bring her to my ship.
最好快點，隊長
Better hustle, Cap.
看來他們這裡要結束了
Things look like they're just about wrapped up here.
瞭解，我正接近電梯
Got it. I'm approaching the elevator now.
如果對你來說沒差…
If it's all the same to you...
我現在就喝那杯酒
I'll have that drink now.
好，讓他站起來
All right, get him on his feet.
其他的晚一點再說
We can all stand around posing up a storm later.
盡量清理一下
By the way, feel free to clean up.
羅傑斯先生，我差點忘了這套服裝…
Mr. Rogers, I almost forgot that that suit...
完全沒讓你屁股變翹
did nothing for your ass.
沒人叫你看，東尼
No one asked you to look, Tony.
-太可笑了 -你很帥，隊長
It's ridiculous. I think you look great, Cap.
我認為那就是美國翹臀
As far as I'm concerned, that's America's ass.
誰拿魔杖？
Who gets the, uh, magic wand?
神盾局團隊來保護它了
S.T.R.I.K.E. team's coming to secure it.
我們能幫妳保管
We can take that off your hands.
請便
By all means.
小心那玩意
Careful with that thing.
除非你想讓心智被抹除
Yeah, unless you want your mind erased.
那可不好玩
And not in a fun way.
我們保證會小心
We promise to be careful.
這些人是誰？
Who are these guys?
他們是神盾局的
They are S.H.I.E.L.D.
其實是九頭蛇，但當時我們不知道
Well, actually Hydra, but we didn't know that yet.
真假？你們不知道？
Seriously? You didn't?
他們一副壞蛋臉
I mean, they look like bad guys.
你個子小，嗓門卻很大
You're small, but you're talking loud.
我下去協調搜救行動
On my way down to coordinate search and rescue.
說真的，你怎麼沒吐出來？
I mean, honestly, how do you keep your food down?
閉嘴
Shut up.
該你上場了，小兄弟
Ooh. All right, you're up, little buddy.
我們的寶石在那裡
There's our stone.
好
All right.
彈我出去
Flick me.
讓開
- Move. - Hey.
兄弟
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! - Hey, hey. Buddy!
你覺得呢？已達人數上限
What do you think? Maximum occupancy has been reached.
走樓梯
Take the stairs.
對啊，停…
Yeah. Stop, stop.
走樓梯，我討厭樓梯
"Take the stairs." Hate the stairs.
隊長，我看到權杖在電梯裡
All right, Cap, I got our sceptre in the elevator...
剛經過80樓
just passing the 80th floor.
馬上去
On it.
-前往大廳 -到那裡見
Head to the lobby. All right,
證據安全無虞
I'll see you there. Evidence secure.
我們正要去找李斯特博士
We're en route to Doctor List.
完全沒耽誤，局長
No. No hitches at all, Mr. Secretary.
隊長
Captain.
我以為你在協調搜救行動
I thought you were coordinating
計畫有變
search and rescue. Change of plans.
隊長
Hey, Cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
我剛接到局長的電話
I just got a call from the secretary.
由我主導保護權杖的行動
I'm gonna be running point on the sceptre.
長官？我不懂
Sir? I don't understand.
據說有人想竊取它
We got word there may be an attempt to steal it.
抱歉，隊長
Sorry, Cap.
權杖不能交給你
We can't give you the sceptre.
我必須聯絡局長
I'm gonna have to call the director.
沒關係，相信我
That's okay. Trust me.
九頭蛇萬歲
Hail Hydra.
好多階樓梯！
So many stairs!
拇指姑娘，收到了嗎？我看到目標了
Thumbelina, do you copy? I've got eyes on the prize.
該行動了
It is go time.
馬上去
Bombs away.
那是體香劑嗎？
Is that Axe Body Spray?
我桌子有一罐以備不時之需，放輕鬆
Yeah, I had a can in the desk for emergencies. Relax.
可以專心點嗎？
Can we focus, please?
我要進入你體內…
I'm going inside you...
現在
now.
請問你們要去哪裡？
Uh, may I ask you where you're going?
先吃午飯再去阿斯嘉，你是？
Bit of lunch and then Asgard. I'm sorry, you are...?
亞歷山大皮爾斯
Alexander Pierce.
他是尼克福瑞背後那批人的上級
He's the man above the folks - behind Nick Fury. - Oh.
我朋友叫我局長先生
My friends call me Mr. Secretary.
我得要求你把那位囚犯交給我
I'm gonna have to ask you to turn that prisoner over to me.
洛基會向奧丁本人報到
Uh, Loki will be answering to Odin himself.
他向我們報到，其他人可交給奧丁
No, he's going to answer to us. Odin can have what's left.
我也需要那個手提箱
And I'm gonna need that case.
70多年來它都是神盾局財產
That's been S.H.I.E.L.D. property for over 70 years.
手提箱交出來，史塔克
Hand over the case, Stark.
動作快，一家之鼠，情況變棘手，快
All right, move it, Stuart Little. Things are getting dicey out here. Let's go.
我不想爭論誰層級較高…
I'm not gonna argue who's got the higher authority here...
你保證你不會死？
You promise me you won't die?
我只會輕微心律不整
We're only giving me a mild cardiac dysrhythmia.
聽起來並不輕微
That doesn't sound mild.
我需要那個箱子
I need the case.
我知道你很大咖，但是管轄權…
I know you got a lot of pull, I'm just saying,
那就把箱子給我
- jurisdiction... - Okay, then give me the case.
-管轄權… -交出來
Well, jurisdiction...
快點！朗恩
Hand it over. Do it, Lang!
-放開我 -沒時間了，拉我的開關
Get your hands off me. Window's closing. Pull my pin.
來囉
Here goes!
-史塔克？ -史塔克？
- Stark? - Stark?
他在抽搐，讓他透透氣
He's convulsing. Give him air!
-醫護員 -醫護員
- Medic! - Medic!
過來幫忙
Give these guys some help.
說話啊
Speak to me.
史塔克，是你胸部的機器嗎？
Stark, is it your chest machine?
呼吸…
Breathe, breathe.
很好，小巷見，我去吃片披薩
Good job. Meet me in the alley. I'm gonna grab a quick slice.
不要走樓梯！
No stairs!
史塔克，撐下去
Uh... Come on, Stark, stay with us.
我要試一個辦法，不知道有沒有用
I'm going to try something. Okay? I have no idea if it's going to work.
太好了！
Yes!
一拍見效
Oh, that worked a treat.
好誇張
Dude, that was so crazy.
我也不知道有沒有用
I had no idea if that was gonna work.
-手提箱 -手提箱…
- The case. - The case is, uh...
手提箱在哪？洛基呢？
Where's the case? Where's Loki?
洛基！
Loki!
那不該發生吧？
That wasn't supposed to happen, was it?
我們搞砸了
Oh, we blew it.
洛基？
Loki?
東尼，怎麼回事？
Tony, what's going on?
跟我說你找到了那方塊
Tell me you found that Cube.
開什麼玩笑
Oh, you gotta be shitting me.
我看到洛基，14樓
I have eyes on Loki. 14th floor.
我不是洛基
I'm not Loki...
我不想傷害你
and I don't wanna hurt you.
我可以陪你慢慢玩
I can do this all day.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
I know.
你怎麼有這個？
Where did you get this?
巴奇還活著
Bucky is alive.
什麼？
What?
明明就是美國翹臀
That is America's ass.
求求妳
Please, please.
抱歉我幫不上忙，布魯斯
I'm sorry, I can't help you, Bruce.
放棄時間寶石來幫助你的現實，會危及我自己
If I give up the Time Stone to help your reality, I'm dooming my own.
我有話直說
With all due respect, all right...
我覺得科學無法支持這一點
I'm not sure the science really supports that.
無限寶石創造了你體驗到的時間流
The Infinity Stones create what you experience as the flow of time.
移除一顆寶石
Remove one of the stones...
時間流便會分裂
and that flow splits.
它或許有利於你的現實
Now, this may benefit your reality...
卻不利我的新現實
but my new one, not so much.
在這新的分支現實
In this new branch reality...
少了對抗黑暗力量的主要武器
without our chief weapon against the forces of darkness...
我們的世界將慘遭蹂躪
our world would be overrun.
千百萬人將受苦受難
Millions will suffer.
告訴我，博士
So, tell me, Doctor.
你的科學能預防這一切嗎？
Can your science prevent all that?
不能
No...
但我們能抹除它
but we can erase it.
一旦取回寶石
Because once we're done with the stones...
我們能將它們送回自己的時間軸
we can return each one to its own timeline...
回到它們被奪走的時刻
at the moment it was taken.
所以，在時間上
So, chronologically...
在那個現實裡
in that reality...
它從未離開
it never left.
但你遺漏了最重要的部分
Yes, but you're leaving out the most important part.
想要送回寶石，你們必須存活
In order to return the stones, you have to survive.
我們會的，我會，我保證
We will. I will. I promise.
我不能靠保證讓這個現實冒險
I can't risk this reality on a promise.
保護時間寶石是至尊魔法師的責任
It's the duty of the Sorcerer Supreme to protect the Time Stone.
那史傳奇為何把它交出去？
Then why the hell did Strange give it away?
你說什麼？
What did you say?
史傳奇，他把它交給薩諾斯
Strange. He gave it away. He gave it to Thanos.
-自願的？ -對
- Willingly? - Yes.
-為什麼？ -我不知道
- Why? - I have no idea.
或許他犯了錯
Maybe he made a mistake.
也許是我犯了錯
Or I did.
史傳奇應該是我們當中最優秀的
Strange is meant to be the best of us.
那他那麼做必定有原因
So, he must've done it for a reason.
恐怕沒錯
I fear you might be right.
謝謝
Thank you.
我就指望你了，布魯斯
I'm counting on you, Bruce.
我們都是
We all are.
進行診斷
Run diagnostics.
呈現她的記憶檔案
Show me her memory file.
老大，檔案顯得非常亂
Sire, the file appears entangled.
是記憶，卻不是她的
It was a memory, but not hers.
有另一個意識…
There's another consciousness...
在共用她的網絡
sharing her network.
另一個涅布拉
Another Nebula.
不可能
Impossible.
這個分身有一個時間戳記
This duplicate carries a time stamp...
來自九年後
from nine years in the future.
另一個涅布拉在哪裡？
Where is this other Nebula?
在我們太陽系，莫拉格星
In our solar system on Morag.
你能進入她的記憶嗎？
Can you access her?
可以，兩者相連
Yes, the two are linked.
搜尋分身的記憶…
Search the duplicate's memories...
找出無限寶石
for Infinity Stones.
這些寶石在歷史上許多地方出現過
And these stones have been in a lot of different places throughout history.
我們的歷史
Our history.
容易前往的時間點…
So, not a lot of convenient spots
並不多
to just drop in.
所以我們必須挑選目標
Which means we have to pick our targets.
-沒錯 -暫停影像
- Correct. - Freeze image.
地球人
Terrans.
復仇者聯盟
Avengers.
任性的下流胚子
Unruly wretches.
那反射影像是什麼？
What's that reflection?
強化它，烏木喉
Amplify this, Maw.
我不懂
I don't understand.
兩個涅布拉
Two Nebulas.
不，同一個涅布拉
No. The same Nebula...
來自兩個不同時間
from two different times.
航向莫拉格星
Set course for Morag.
掃描分身的記憶
And scan the duplicate's memories.
我想看個一清二楚
I wanna see everything.
回頭見，妳們走吧
My ladies, I'll see you after. I'll see you after. Go on ahead.
你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
天啊
Oh, God!
不要學你弟偷溜
You're better off leaving the sneaking to your brother.
我沒有偷溜，我想去散步
No, I wasn't sneaking. I was just going for a walk.
你穿這是什麼？
What are you wearing?
我常穿這個，我最喜歡的
I always wear this. It's one of my favourites.
你眼睛怎麼了？
Mm... What's wrong with your eye?
我的眼睛
Oh, my eye.
記得哈洛金戰役
Remember the, uh, Battle of Harokin...
我的臉被大刀砍傷嗎？
when I got hit in the face with the broadsword?
你根本不是我認識的索爾吧？
You're not the Thor I know at all, are you?
我是
Yes, I am.
你在未來過得不好，對吧？
The future hasn't been kind to you, has it?
我沒說我來自未來
I didn't say I was from the future.
我是女巫養大的，孩子
I was raised by witches, boy.
你知道我不只用眼睛看
I see with more than eyes, you know that.
對，我就是來自未來
Yeah, I'm totally from the future.
你是，親愛的
Yes, you are, honey.
我真的很需要跟妳談
I really need to talk to you.
我們可以談談
We can talk.
他的頭在那裡
His head was over there...
身體在那邊
and his body over there...
有什麼意義呢？我太遲了
I mean, what was the point? I was too late.
我只是杵在那裡
I was just standing there.
一個拿著斧頭的白癡
Some idiot with an axe.
你不是白癡
Now, you're no idiot.
你不是來了嗎？
You're here, aren't you?
向阿斯嘉最睿智的人徵詢意見
Seeking counsel from the wisest person in Asgard.
對
I am. Yes.
白癡，不是
Idiot, no.
失敗者？
A failure?
當然
Absolutely.
有點傷人
That's a little bit harsh.
這讓你成了什麼呢？
Do you know what that makes you?
跟其他人沒兩樣
Just like everyone else.
我不該跟其他人沒兩樣吧？
I'm not supposed to be like everyone else, am I?
每個人都無法成為理想中的自己，索爾
Mm. Everyone fails at who they're supposed to be, Thor.
衡量一個人，一個英雄
The measure of a person, of a hero...
要看他們是否成功做自己
is how well they succeed at being who they are.
我真的好想妳，媽
I've really missed you, Mom.
索爾！我拿到了
Thor! I got it!
抓住那隻兔子
Get that rabbit!
媽，我得告訴妳一件事
Mom, I have to tell you something.
兒子，你不必說
No, son, you don't.
你是來修補你的未來，不是我的
You're here to repair your future, not mine.
這關乎妳的未來
This is about your future.
與我無關
Uh, it's none of my business.
妳好
Hi.
妳一定是索爾的媽
You must be Mom.
我拿到了，我們快走
I got the thing. Come on. We gotta move.
真希望能留久一點
Oh, I wish we had more time.
不，這是上天的恩賜
No, this was a gift.
去承擔你該當的角色吧
Now you go and be the man you're meant to be.
我愛妳，媽
I love you, Mom.
我愛你
I love you.
多吃沙拉
And eat a salad.
我們該走了
Come on, we gotta go.
-再見 -三…
- Goodbye. - Three...
-二… -不，等等！
- Two... - No, wait!
現在是怎樣？
What am I looking at?
有時需要一下子
Oh, sometimes it takes a second.
我還有資格
I'm still worthy.
天啊
Oh, boy.
-再見，媽 -再見
- Goodbye, Mom. - Goodbye.
所以他是白癡？
So, he's an idiot?
嗯
Yeah.
那是什麼？
What's that?
小偷的傢伙
The tool of a thief.
這時牆面會有尖刺伸出來
Whoa, whoa, whoa. This is the part where spikes come out...
尾端還有骷髏
with skeletons on the end of them and everything.
你在說什麼？
What are you talking about?
闖入力量寶石神殿時
When you break into a place called "The Temple of the Power Stone"...
一定會有不少陷阱
there's gonna be a bunch of booby traps.
-天啊 -好吧，妳走吧
- Oh, my God. - Okay. All right. Go ahead.
我並非一直這副模樣
I wasn't always like this.
我也不是
Me either.
我們只能物盡其用，對吧？
But we work with what we got, right?
一起
Hmm. Let's sync up.
三，二，一
Three, two, one.
你謀殺了數十億人
You murdered trillions!
你應該心存感激
You should be grateful.
寶石在哪裡？
Where are the stones?
灰飛煙滅
Gone.
縮小成原子
Reduced to atoms.
兩天前你才用過它們
You used them two days ago!
我用寶石來摧毀寶石
I used the stones to destroy the stones.
差點害我沒命
It nearly killed me.
但任務結束了
But the work is done.
總是會結束的
It always will be.
我是無可匹敵的
I am inevitable.
你對他們做了什麼？
What did you do to them?
沒有
Nothing.
還沒
Yet.
他們不是想阻止我即將做的事
They're not trying to stop something I'm going to do in our time.
他們想逆轉我在他們那時候已經做的事
They're trying to undo something I've already done in theirs.
寶石
The stones.
我全都找到了
I found them all.
我贏了
I won.
讓宇宙達到平衡
Tipped the cosmic scales to balance.
這是您的未來
This is your future.
這是我的天命
It's my destiny.
我父親有很多面向
My father is many things.
卻不會說謊
A liar is not one of them.
謝謝妳，女兒
Ah. Thank you, daughter.
或許我對妳太嚴厲了
Perhaps I treated you too harshly.
天命就此實現
And that is destiny fulfilled.
老大
Sire...
您女兒…
your daughter...
不！
No!
是叛徒
...is a traitor.
那不是我，我不可能…
That's not me. It's not, I could never...
我絕對不會背叛你
I would never betray you.
絕對不會
Never. Never.
我知道
I know.
妳會有機會證明的
And you'll have the chance to prove it.
糟糕
No!
他知道了
He knows!
巴頓…請回答
Barton! Barton, come in.
羅曼諾夫
Romanoff!
請回答，我們碰上麻煩了
Come in, we have a problem.
快啊
Come on!
請回答，我們碰上…
Come in, we have a...
薩諾斯知道了
Thanos knows.
薩諾斯…
Thanos...
隊長
Cap.
抱歉，我們碰上問題了
Sorry, buddy, we got a problem.
真的
Yeah, we do.
現在怎麼辦？
Well, what are we gonna do now?
饒了我吧，史帝夫
You know what? Give me a break, Steve.
我的頭剛挨了浩克一拳
I just got hit in the head with the Hulk.
你說我們只有一次機會
You said that we had one shot.
這就是我們的機會
This was our shot.
我們試過了，不拿到六顆就沒用
We shot it. It's shot. Six stones or nothing.
-不拿到六顆就沒用 -你在鬼打牆
- It was six stones or nothing. - You're repeating yourself,
你在鬼打牆
you know that? You're repeating yourself.
你才在鬼打牆…
You're repeating yourself. You're repeating yourself.
-拜託 -你根本不要時間攔劫
Dude. Come on! No. You never wanted a time heist.
你不贊成時間攔劫
You weren't on board with the time heist.
-我錯了 -你毀了時間攔劫
- I dropped the ball. - You ruined the time heist.
-我有嗎？ -有
- Is that what I did? - Yeah.
有別的辦法能拿到宇宙魔方嗎？
Are there any other options with the Tesseract?
沒有別的辦法
No, no, no, there's no other options.
不能重來
There's no do-overs.
我們不能亂跑，只剩一管粒子
We're not going anywhere else. We have one particle left.
每人一管
Each.
就這樣，懂嗎？只要用了…
That's it. All right? We use that...
掰掰，你們就別想回家
bye-bye, you're not going home.
如果我們不嘗試
Yeah, well, if we don't try...
誰都別想回家
then no one else is going home, either.
我想到了
I got it.
有辦法能拿回宇宙魔方，取得新的粒子
There's another way to retake the Tesseract and acquire new particles.
回憶一下往事
Little stroll down memory lane.
軍事設施，紐澤西州
Military installation, Garden State.
他們倆都在那邊的時候？
When were they both there?
他們曾經在那裡，我有點模糊
They were there at a time... I have a vaguely exact idea.
-多模糊？ -你們說什麼？
- How vague? - What are you talking about?
我們要去哪？
Where are we going?
我確定他們在那裡
I know for a fact they were there.
-誰啊？這幹嘛？ -我知道我怎麼知道的
Who's they? What are we doing? And I know how I know.
到底是怎樣？
Guys, what is it?
看來我們要隨機應變
Looks like we're improvising.
-太好了 -隨機應變什麼？
- Great. - What are we improvising?
史考特，把這拿回總部
Scott, get this back to the compound.
整裝
Suit up.
-紐澤西有什麼？ -04
- What's in New Jersey? - 0-4.
0-4.
-07
-請問一下 -1970 - Uh, 0-7.
- 0-7. - Excuse me. - 1-9-7-0.
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
隊長？
Cap? Captain?
史帝夫？抱歉
Steve? Sorry.
美國…羅傑斯
America. Rogers.
如果這麼做
Look, if you do this...
卻沒用，你們就回不來了
and it doesn't work, you're not coming back.
謝謝你的鼓勵，小蟻子
Thanks for the pep talk, pissant.
你相信我嗎？
You trust me?
相信
I do.
你決定
Your call.
出發吧
Here we go.
（紐澤西，1970年）
（說夠了）
老兄！做愛不打仗
Hey, man! Make love, not war.
（美國陸軍勒海營基地）
（第78步兵師，美國隊長誕生地）
顯然你不是在這裡出生吧？
Clearly you weren't actually born here, right?
我的概念是
The idea of me was.
假設你是神盾局
Right. Well, imagine you're S.H.I.E.L.D...
運作一個類法西斯情報組織
running a quasi-fascistic intelligence organization...
你會藏在哪裡？
where do you hide it?
近在眼前
In plain sight.
祝你任務順利，隊長
Good luck on your mission, Captain.
祝你計畫順利，博士
Good luck on your project, Doctor.
新來的嗎？
You new here?
不算
Not exactly.
快啊，混蛋
Come on, you bastard.
（伽瑪特徵不符）
（目標相符）
找到了
Gotcha.
Whew.
重回戰場
Back in the game.
阿尼姆，你在裡面嗎？
Arnim, you in there?
阿尼姆？
Arnim?
喂！
Hey!
門在這邊，老兄
The door is this way, pal.
對喔
Oh, yeah.
我在找左拉博士，有看到他嗎？
Looking for Doctor Zola, have you seen him?
左拉博士…我沒看到任何人
Yeah, Doctor Zola. No, I haven't seen a soul.
不好意思
Pardon me.
我們認識嗎？
Do I know you?
不認識
No, sir. Uh...
我從麻省理工學院來訪
I'm a visitor from MIT.
麻省理工學院
Oh. MIT.
大名？
Got a name?
霍華
Howard.
-很好記 -霍華…
- That'll be easy to remember. - Howard...
波茲
Potts.
我是霍華史塔克
Well, I'm Howard Stark.
你好
Hi.
握手，別拉手指
Shake that, don't pull it.
是
Yeah.
你看來氣色不太好，波茲
You look a little green around the gills, there, Potts.
我很好，只是上班累了
I'm fine. Just long hours.
想出去透透氣嗎？
You wanna get some air?
-喂，波茲 -是
- Hello, Potts. - Yeah.
-好啊 -這邊請
- That'd be swell. - That way.
好
Okay.
需要拿公事包嗎？
Need your briefcase?
你不是披頭族吧，波茲？
You're not one of those beatniks, are you, Potts?
-喂？ -皮姆博士？
- Hello? - Doctor Pym?
你打的號碼沒錯，是
That would be the number that you called, yes.
我是快遞公司的史帝芬斯隊長
This is Captain Stevens from shipping.
有你的包裹
We have a package for you.
拿上來
Oh, bring it up.
問題就在這，沒辦法
That's the thing, sir, we can't.
我不懂，那不是你的工作嗎？
I'm confused. I thought that was your job.
因為…
Well, it's just...
先生，這箱子在發光
Sir, the box is glowing...
我們有些快遞員覺得不舒服
and to be honest, some of our mail guys aren't feeling that great.
他們沒打開箱子吧？
They didn't open it, did they?
有，你最好下來
Uh, yeah, they did. You better get down here.
借過，讓開
Excuse me! Out of the way!
（亨利皮姆博士）
（皮姆粒子，請勿碰觸）
鮮花和德國酸菜，晚上有重要約會嗎？
So, flowers and sauerkraut. You got a big date tonight?
我太太懷孕了
Uh, my wife's expecting.
我花太多時間在辦公室
And too much time at the office.
恭喜
Congratulations.
-謝謝，麻煩拿一下 -沒問題
- Thanks. Hold this, will ya? - Yeah, sure.
-她懷孕幾個月？ -不知道
- How far along is she? - Uh, I don't know.
目前她受不了我嚼東西的聲音
She's at the point where she can't stand the sound of my chewing.
我又得在廚房角落吃晚餐了
I guess I'll be eating dinner in the pantry again.
我有個女兒
I have a little girl.
生女兒不錯
A girl would be nice.
比較不會變得跟我一個樣
Less of a chance she'd turn out exactly like me.
那有什麼不好？
What'd be so awful about that?
我認為我通常是個自私的人
Let's just say that the greater good has rarely outweighed my own self-interest.
妳沒見過這兩個人？
And you've never seen these two men before?
我直覺很準，他們倆怪怪的
No, I've got an eye for this. The two of them looked fishy.
-長什麼樣子？ -一個留嬉皮鬍鬚
Can you describe them? One of them had a hippie beard.
嬉皮，像比吉斯還是蒙哥傑瑞？
Hippie. Like Bee Gees or Mungo Jerry?
很像蒙哥傑瑞
Definitely Mungo Jerry.
我是契斯勒，請所有憲兵到地下六樓
Yeah, this is Chesler. I need every available MP to sublevel six.
可能有外人闖入
We have a potential breach.
（瑪格麗特卡特，局長）
我說把他們轉過來
I said bring them in.
他們在想辦法，
They're trying, ma'am, but Braddock's unit
但布拉多克的小組因雷擊受阻
has been stopped by lightning strikes.
真是的
Oh, for the love of...
我來看看氣象預報
I'll look at the weather projections.
情況不是雷擊
It's not lightning strikes we're looking at.
你們想好名字了嗎？
So, where you at with names?
如果是男生，我太太喜歡艾蒙佐
Well, if it's a boy, my wife likes Elmonzo. Huh.
再考慮一下，還有時間
Might wanna let that stew awhile. You got time. - Uh-huh.
問你一個問題
Let me ask you a question.
小孩出生時，你緊張嗎？
When your kid was born, were you nervous?
快瘋了
Wildly.
-嗯 -你覺得自己夠格嗎？
- Yeah. - Did you feel qualified?
你知道如何當個成功的父親嗎？
Like you had any idea how to successfully operate that thing?
我一路走來邊做邊學
I literally pieced it together as I went along.
回想我爸的做法
I thought about what my dad did.
我老爸一律用皮帶解決問題
My old man, he never met a problem he couldn't solve with a belt.
我以為我爸對我很嚴格
I thought my dad was tough on me.
如今回想起來，我只記得好的事情
And now, looking back on it, I just remember the good stuff.
他說過一些至理名言
You know? He did drop the odd pearl.
是嗎？譬如說？
Yeah? Like what?
金錢買不到時間
"No amount of money ever bought a second of time."
有智慧
Smart guy.
他盡力了
He did his best.
孩子還沒出生，我已願為他付出一切
I'll tell you, that kid's not even here yet and there's nothing I wouldn't do for him.
幸會，波茲
Good to meet you, Potts.
嗯
Yeah.
霍華
Howard...
一切都會很順利的
everything's gonna be all right.
謝謝你…
Thank you...
所做的一切…
for everything...
為我們國家效力
you've done for this country.
老賈
Jarvis.
我們見過那個人嗎？
Have we ever met that guy?
您見過很多人，先生
You meet a lot of people, sir.
看來非常面熟
Seems very familiar.
奇怪的鬍子
Weird beard.
妳真弱
You're weak.
我是妳
I'm you.
妳可以阻止這件事
You could stop this.
妳知道妳想阻止它
You know you want to.
妳看到未來發生的情況了嗎？
Did you see what happens in the future?
薩諾斯找到靈魂寶石
Thanos finds the Soul Stone.
想知道他怎麼找到的嗎？
You wanna know how he does that?
想知道他怎麼對妳的嗎？
You wanna know what he does to you?
夠了
That's enough.
妳令我覺得噁心
You disgust me.
但這不代表妳毫無用處
But that doesn't mean you're useless.
我看起來如何？
How do I look?
（佛米爾星，2014年）
哇
Wow.
要是情況不同
Under different circumstances...
這會讓人十分驚豔
this would be totally awesome.
我敢說那隻浣熊不必爬山
I bet the raccoon didn't have to climb a mountain.
嚴格說來他不是浣熊
Technically he's not a raccoon, you know?
隨便，他都吃垃圾
Oh, whatever. He eats garbage.
歡迎
Welcome.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
伊凡之女
Daughter of Ivan.
克林特
Clint.
伊蒂絲之子
Son of Edith.
你是誰？
Who are you?
就把我當成嚮導…
Consider me a guide...
帶領你們…
to you...
以及所有尋找靈魂寶石的人
and to all who seek the Soul Stone.
很好
Oh, good.
說出它的下落，我們就啟程
You tell us where it is, then we'll be on our way.
有那麼簡單就好了
If only it were that easy.
你們尋找的就在你們眼前
What you seek lies in front of you.
你們所恐懼的也是
As does what you fear.
寶石在下面
The stone's down there.
你們其中一人能帶走
For one of you.
至於另一個…
For the other...
若想拿到寶石
In order to take the stone...
就必須失去所愛
you must lose that which you love.
一項永恆的交易
An everlasting exchange.
以靈魂換取靈魂
A soul for a soul.
你好嗎？
How's it going?
天啊
Jesus.
也許他是瞎掰的
Maybe he's making this shit up.
不
No.
我覺得不是
I don't think so.
因為他知道妳爸的名字嗎？
Why? 'Cause he knows your daddy's name?
我不知道他的名字
I didn't.
薩諾斯帶走寶石
Thanos left here with the stone...
卻沒帶女兒走
without his daughter.
那不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
是啊
Yeah.
不計代價
Whatever it takes.
如果不拿到那顆寶石
If we don't get that stone...
數十億人無法起死回生
billions of people stay dead.
是啊
Yeah.
我想我們都知道應該是誰
Then I guess we both know who it's gotta be.
沒錯
I guess we do.
我開始覺得我們指的是不同人，娜塔莎
I'm starting to think we mean different people here, Natasha.
五年來，我一直想做一件事
For the last five years, I've been trying to do one thing.
來到這裡
Get to right here.
達成目標，將所有人救回來
That's all it's been about. Bringing everybody back.
不准擺出正義女俠的樣子
No, don't you get all decent on me now.
你以為我想做嗎？
What, you think I wanna do it?
我是想救你，白癡
I'm trying to save your life, you idiot.
我不要妳去，如何？
Yeah, well, I don't want you to. How's that?
娜塔莎，妳知道我做過什麼
Natasha, you know what I've done.
妳知道我背負的罪
You know what I've become.
我不憑別人的大錯來評斷他們
Oh, I don't judge people on their worst mistakes.
或許妳應該
Maybe you should.
你就沒有
You didn't.
妳讓我很傷腦筋，知道嗎？
You're a pain in my ass, you know that?
好吧
Okay.
妳贏了
You win.
告訴我家人我愛他們
Tell my family I love 'em.
你自己告訴他們
You tell 'em yourself.
可惡
Damn you.
等等
Wait.
放開我
Let me go.
不
No.
不，求求妳
No. Please, no.
沒關係
It's okay.
求求妳
Please.
不！
No!
全都拿到了嗎？
Did we get 'em all?
你是說真的成功了？
Are you telling me this actually worked?
克林特，小娜呢？
Clint, where's Nat?
她有家人嗎？
Do we know if she had family?
有
Yeah.
我們
Us.
怎麼了？
What?
-你在幹嘛？ -問他問題
Huh? - What are you doing? - Just asked him a question.
你一副她死了的樣子
Yeah, no, you're acting like she's dead.
何必如喪考妣？我們有寶石啊
Why are we acting like she's dead? We have the stones, right?
只要我們有寶石…
As long as we have the stones...
就能救她回來，不是嗎？
Cap, we can bring her back. Isn't that right?
別這樣，我們是復仇者聯盟，振作
So, stop this shit. We're the Avengers. Get it together.
我們不能救她回來
Can't get her back.
什麼？
What's he...? What?
那無法逆轉
It can't be undone.
沒辦法
It can't.
抱歉，恕我直說，你是凡人
Look, I'm sorry, no offence, but you're a very earthly being, okay?
我們說的是太空魔法
And we're talking about space magic.
講"無法"好像太鐵齒了
And "can't" seems very definitive. Don't you think?
我知道我層次不夠高
Yeah, look, I know that I'm way outside my pay grade here.
但她還是不在這裡
But she still isn't here, is she?
這就是我要講的
No, that's my point.
它無法逆轉
It can't be undone.
至少那個紅色漂浮人是這麼說的
Or that's at least what the red, floating guy had to say.
你可以去找他談
Maybe you wanna go talk to him, okay?
拿你的鎚子飛去找他談
Go grab your hammer and you go fly and you talk to him.
原本應該是我
It was supposed to be me.
她為那顆寶石犧牲生命
She sacrificed her life for that goddamn stone.
她賭上自己的命
She bet her life on it.
她不會回來了
She's not coming back.
我們得讓她犧牲得有價值
We have to make it worth it.
重如泰山
We have to.
我們會的
We will.
砰！
Boom!
手套準備好了
All right, the glove's ready.
問題是誰來彈指？
Question is, who's gonna snap their freakin' fingers?
-我來 -什麼？
- I'll do it. - Excuse me?
沒關係
It's okay.
別急
Stop, stop. Slow down.
索爾，等一下
Thor. Just wait.
我們還沒決定誰戴手套
We haven't decided who's gonna put that on yet.
抱歉，我們還要坐等適當時機嗎？
I'm sorry. What, we're all just sitting around waiting for the right opportunity?
至少應該討論一下
We should at least discuss it.
盯著那東西看不能救所有人回來
Look, sitting here staring at the thing is not gonna bring everybody back.
我是最強的復仇者，就該擔起責任
I'm the strongest Avenger, okay? So, this responsibility falls upon me.
-平常是那樣沒錯 -我的責任
- Normally, you're right. - It's my duty.
-重點不在那 -不是那樣
- It's not about that. - It's not that.
-兄弟 -閉嘴！讓我來
- Hey, buddy... - Stop it! Just let me.
讓我來
Just let me do it.
讓我做件好事，對的事
Just let me do something good. Something right.
這手套發出的能量
Look, it's not just the fact...
不僅足以供電給整座大陸
that that glove is channeling enough energy to light up a continent.
你的狀況也不理想
I'm telling you. You're in no condition.
你想我血管裡現在流著什麼？
What do you think is coursing through my veins right now?
起司醬？
Cheez Whiz?
閃電
Lightning.
-對 -閃電
Yeah. Lightning.
閃電幫不了你，兄弟
Lightning won't help you, pal.
應該是我
It's gotta be me.
你們看到哪些寶石對薩諾斯的影響
You saw what those stones did to Thanos.
它們差點殺死他
They almost killed him.
你們都無法存活
None of you could survive.
我們怎麼知道你可以？
How do we know you will?
不知道
We don't.
但那輻射主要是伽瑪
But the radiation's mostly gamma.
看來…
It's like...
我就是最佳人選
I was made for this.
可以了嗎？
Good to go, yeah?
動手吧
Let's do it.
記住，薩諾斯五年前殺害的所有人
Okay, remember, everyone Thanos snapped away five years ago...
你只能將他們帶回到今天
you're just bringing them back to now, today.
別改變過去五年的任何事
Don't change anything from the last five years.
瞭解
Got it.
星期五，幫我啟動穀倉門協定
Friday, do me a favour and activate Barn Door Protocol, will ya?
是，老闆
Yes, boss.
大家回來吧
Everybody comes home.
脫掉…
Take it off! Take it off!
等等，布魯斯，你還好嗎？
No, wait. Bruce, are you okay?
說話，班納
Talk to me, Banner.
我沒事
I'm okay.
（入口開啟，原點2014年）
布魯斯
Bruce!
別動他
Don't move him.
-成功了嗎？ -不確定，沒關係
- Did it work? - We're not sure. It's okay.
（蘿拉）
親愛的
克林特？
Honey. Clint?
親愛的
Honey.
大夥
Guys...
我想成功了
I think it worked.
我不能呼吸…
I can't breathe! I can't breathe!
頭罩…
Canopy, canopy, canopy.
羅德、火箭，快離開
Rhodey, Rocket, get out of here.
讓我上去…
Let me up! Let me up!
快啊！
Come on!
羅德
Rhodey!
Huh?
求救…有人收到嗎？我們在下層，淹水了
Mayday, Mayday! Does anybody copy? We're on the lower level. It's flooding!
什麼？
What? What?
我們溺水了，有人收到嗎？求救
We are drowning! Does anybody copy? Mayday!
等等，我在
Wait! I'm here!
我在，聽到了嗎？
I'm here. Can you hear me?
隊長？
Cap?
好
Okay.
女兒
Daughter.
是，父親
Yes, Father.
所以這就是未來
So, this is the future.
幹得好
Well done.
謝謝父親
Thank you, Father.
他們完全沒起疑
They suspected nothing.
傲慢者從不起疑
The arrogant never do.
去吧
Go.
去找寶石，拿來給我
Find the stones, bring them to me.
你會怎麼做？
What will you do?
等待
Wait.
告訴我一件事
Tell me something.
在未來…
In the future...
妳和我會怎麼樣？
what happens to you and me?
我企圖殺妳
I try to kill you.
好幾次
Several times.
但最後…
But eventually...
我們成為朋友
we become friends.
成為姊妹
We become sisters.
走吧
Come on.
我們能阻止他
We can stop him.
快醒醒
Come on, buddy, wake up!
這才對
That's my man.
你又弄丟了這個，我留著
You lose this again, I'm keeping it.
怎麼回事？
What happened?
改變時間往往會造成問題
You mess with time, it tends to mess back.
等會就知道
You'll see.
他在做什麼？
What's he been doing?
什麼都沒做
Absolutely nothing.
無限寶石呢？
Where are the stones?
在這片瓦礫堆底下
Somewhere under all this.
我只知道不在他手中
All I know is he doesn't have 'em.
那就保持下去
So, we keep it that way.
你們知道這是陷阱吧？
You know it's a trap, right?
是啊
Yeah.
管不了那麼多
I don't much care.
很好
Good.
只要我們有共識就好
Just as long as we're all in agreement.
這次讓他死得痛快
Let's kill him properly this time.
你們無法受失敗
You could not live with your own failure.
結果是什麼？
Where did that bring you?
再和我決一死戰
Back to me.
我以為殲滅半數生命
I thought by eliminating half of life...
另一半會成長茁壯
the other half would thrive.
但你們讓我看到…
But you've shown me...
那是不可能的
that's impossible.
只要有人記得昔日的榮景
And as long as there are those that remember what was...
就必定有人無法接受現實
there will always be those that are unable to accept what can be.
他們會反抗
They will resist.
對，我們就是那麼頑強
Yep, we're all kinds of stubborn.
我很感恩
I'm thankful.
因為現在…
Because now...
我知道自己該怎麼做
I know what I must do.
我將瓦解這宇宙
I will shred this universe...
消滅到最後一個原子不剩
down to its last atom.
然後
And then...
靠你們幫我蒐集來的寶石
with the stones you've collected for me...
創造一個新宇宙
create a new one...
充滿生命
teeming with life...
它知道的不是失去什麼
that knows not what it has lost...
而是獲得什麼
but only what it has been given.
一個懂得感恩的宇宙
A grateful universe.
從鮮血中誕生
Born out of blood.
他們永遠不會知道
They'll never know it.
因為你們不會活著告訴他們
Because you won't be alive to tell them.
另一個世界見了
See you on the other side, man.
等等，我來了
Hang on! I'm coming!
耶！
Yeah!
嗨
Oh, hey.
我認識妳
I know you.
父親
Father...
寶石到手了
I have the stones.
什麼？
What?
住手
Stop.
妳背叛我們？
You're betraying us?
妳不必這麼做
You don't have to do this.
這是我的天命
I am this.
不，並不是
No, you're not.
妳見過我們未來的下場
You've seen what we become.
涅布拉，聽她的話
Nebula, listen to her.
妳能改變
You can change.
他不會讓我改變的
He won't let me.
不！
No!
索爾，打我
Okay, Thor. Hit me.
老闆，醒醒！
Boss, wake up!
我就知道
I knew it!
我多年來的征戰
In all my years of conquest...
暴力
violence...
屠殺
slaughter...
向來不為一己之私
it was never personal.
但我現在告訴你
But I'll tell you now...
當對付你那頑固惱人的小星球時
what I'm about to do to your stubborn, annoying little planet...
我會非常非常…
I'm gonna enjoy it...
樂在其中
very, very much.
隊長，聽到了嗎？
Hey, Cap, you read me?
隊長，我山姆，聽到了嗎？
Cap, it's Sam. Can you hear me?
在你左邊
On your left.
大家都到了嗎？
Is that everyone?
你還嫌不夠嗎？
What? You wanted more?
復仇者聯盟…
Avengers...
集結
assemble.
去死吧！
Die!
不，給我，你拿小的
No, no, give me that. You have the little one.
喂！
Hey!
哇靠
Holy cow!
你不會相信發生了什麼事
You will not believe what's been going on.
記得我們在太空中嗎？
Do you remember when we were in space?
我變成灰燼？
And I got all dusty?
我一定昏倒了，醒來後你就不見了
And I must've passed out, because I woke up and you were gone.
奇異博士在那邊，他說…
But Doctor Strange was there, right? And he was like...
"五年了，快，他們需要我們"
"It's been five years. Come on, they need us."
然後開始像平常那樣畫火圈
And then he started doing the yellow sparkly thing that he does all the time.
是嗎？不
He did? Oh, no.
你幹嘛？
What are you doing? - Oh.
感覺好溫馨
Oh, this is nice.
葛摩菈？
Gamora?
我以為我失去妳了
I thought I lost you.
不要…碰…我
Ow. Don't touch me!
妳第一次沒踢中
You missed the first time.
第二次兩顆都中
Then you got 'em both the second time.
就是這個？
This is the one?
真假？
Seriously?
妳只能挑他或一棵樹
Your choices were him or a tree.
隊長
Cap!
你要我拿這玩意做什麼？
What do you want me to do with this damn thing?
把寶石拿得越遠越好
Get those stones as far away as possible!
不！
No!
我們得將它們送回原處
We need to get 'em back where they came from.
沒辦法，薩諾斯摧毀了量子隧道
No way to get 'em back. Thanos destroyed the quantum tunnel.
等一下
Hold on!
那不是我們唯一的時間機器
That wasn't our only time machine.
有人看到很醜的棕色廂型車嗎？
Anyone see an ugly brown van out there?
有！你不會喜歡它停的地方
Yes! But you're not gonna like where it's parked!
史考特，讓那玩意發揮作用要多久？
Scott, how long you need to get that thing working?
大約十分鐘
Uh, maybe 10 minutes.
開始發動，我們拿寶石給你
Get it started. We'll get the stones to you.
馬上辦，隊長
We're on it, Cap.
嘿
Hey.
你說我們勝率一千四百萬分之一？
You said one out of 14 million, we win, yeah?
告訴我就是這次
Tell me this is it.
如果我告訴你會發生什麼事
If I tell you what happens...
它就不會發生
it won't happen.
你最好是對的
You better be right.
這裡好混亂
It's a mess back here.
車子掛了
It's dead.
-什麼？ -拋錨
- What? - It's dead.
我得接電熱線發動
I have to hot-wire it.
涅布拉呢？
Where's Nebula?
她沒回應
She's not responding.
老大
Sire...
克林特
Clint!
交給我
Give it to me.
你奪走了我的一切
You took everything from me.
我根本不知道妳是哪根蔥
I don't even know who you are.
你會知道的
You will.
交給我
I got it!
啟動速殺模式
Activate Instant Kill.
空中掃射！
Rain fire!
但老大，我們的部隊
But, sire, our troops!
快點！
Just do it!
有人看到這個嗎？
Uh, is anyone else seeing this?
讓我來
I got this!
我來…我不行
I got this. Okay, I don't got this.
救命啊，快救命啊
Help, somebody help!
皇后區小子，注意
Hey, Queens, heads up!
等一下，我來救你
Hang on. I got you, kid.
很高興認識妳
Hey! Nice to meet you...
歐買尬！
Oh, my God!
這是甚麼啊？
What the hell is this?
星期五，他們在射什麼？
Friday, what are they firing at?
有東西進入高層大氣
Something just entered the upper atmosphere.
帥啦！
Oh, yeah!
丹佛斯，這裡需要協助
Danvers, we need an assist here.
妳好，我是彼得帕克
Hi, I'm Peter Parker.
嗨，彼得帕克
Hey, Peter Parker.
有東西要給我嗎？
You got something for me?
我不知道妳要如何對付他們
I don't know how you're gonna get it through all of that.
別擔心
Don't worry.
她有幫手
She's got help.
我是無可匹敵的
I am inevitable.
我…
And I...
是…
am...
鋼鐵人
Iron Man.
史塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
嘿
Hey!
史塔克先生，聽得見嗎？
Mr. Stark. Can you hear me?
我是彼得
It's Peter.
嗨
Hey.
我們贏了，史塔克先生
We won, Mr. Stark.
我們贏了，你成功了…
We won! You did it, sir, you did it.
對不起
I'm sorry.
東尼
Tony.
嗨
Hey.
小辣椒
Hey, Pep.
星期五？
Friday?
生命功能危急
Life functions critical.
東尼
Tony?
看著我
Look at me.
我們會好好的
We're gonna be okay.
你可以休息了
You can rest now.
大家都要快樂結局，對吧？
Everybody wants a happy ending, right?
但不見得總能如願
But it doesn't always roll that way.
或許這次可以
Maybe this time.
我希望如果妳播放這影片
I'm hoping if you play this back...
是為了慶祝
it's in celebration.
我希望家人團聚，我們恢復生機
I hope families are reunited. I hope we get it back.
地球已經回復正常了
And something like a normal version of the planet has been restored.
如果真有所謂正常的地球
If there ever was such a thing.
天啊，我們的世界已是整個宇宙了
God, what a world. Universe, now.
如果十年前妳說人類並不孤單
If you told me 10 years ago that we weren't alone...
更別說到這程度，我並不會驚訝
let alone to this extent, I mean, I wouldn't have been surprised...
但拜託，誰曉得是這樣？
but come on, who knew?
光明與黑暗的驚人力量已發揮作用
The epic forces of darkness and light that have come into play.
無論如何
And for better or worse...
那是摩根在成長時必須面對的現實
that's the reality Morgan's gonna have to find a way to grow up in.
所以我想最好錄一小段祝福
So, I thought I'd probably better record a little greeting...
以防萬一我提早掛掉
in the case of an untimely death. On my part.
雖然任何時候掛掉都不是好時機
Not that death at any time isn't untimely.
我們明天想嘗試的時間旅行
This time travel thing that we're gonna try and pull off tomorrow...
能否存活下來仍在未定之天
it's got me scratching my head about the survivability of it all.
就是這事
That's the thing.
話說回來，這是超級英雄的職責
Then again, that's the hero gig, right?
終點是旅程的一部分
Part of the journey is the end.
我何必緊張？
What am I even tripping for?
一切都會照計畫進行
Everything is gonna work out exactly the way it's supposed to.
我愛妳三千次
I love you 3,000.
（東尼史塔克有心臟的證據）
真希望我有辦法讓她知道
You know, I wish there was a way that I could let her know.
我們贏了
That we won.
我們成功了
We did it.
她知道
She knows.
他們倆都知道
They both do.
妳還好嗎，小可愛？
How you doing, squirt?
很好
Good.
-很好？ -嗯
- You good? - Mm-hmm.
-肚子餓嗎？ -嗯
- Good. You hungry? - Mm-hmm.
想吃什麼？
What do you want?
起司漢堡
Cheeseburgers.
妳爸也愛吃起司漢堡
You know, your dad liked cheeseburgers.
喔
Okay.
想吃多少起司漢堡我都買給妳
I'm gonna get you all the cheeseburgers you want.
好
Okay.
那麼…
So...
你何時要回來？
when can we expect you back?
關於這一點…
Um, about that...
索爾，你的人民需要國王
Thor, your people need a king.
不，他們已經有一個了
No, they already have one.
真好笑
That's funny.
你是認真的嗎？
Are you being serious?
我該做真正的自己了
It's time for me to be who I am...
而非做我該做的那個人
rather than who I'm supposed to be.
但妳是領袖
But you, you're a leader.
優秀而稱職
That's who you are.
我會讓這裡改頭換面
You know, I'd make a lot of changes around here.
我滿心期待
I'm counting on it...
陛下
Your Majesty.
你有什麼打算？
What will you do?
還不確定
I'm not sure.
千年來我第一次沒有方向
For the first time in a thousand years,
不過我能搭便車
I have no path. I do have a ride though.
動作快，乞幫幫主
Move it or lose it, hairbag.
（搜尋中）
到了
Oh, here we are!
樹仔，真高興見到你
Tree, good to see you.
阿斯嘉星際異攻隊再度合體
The Asgardians of the Galaxy back together again.
先去哪裡？
Where to first?
嘿
Hey.
別忘了，這還是我的船
Just so you know, this is my ship still.
我是老大
I'm in charge.
我知道，當然
I know. I know. Of course you are.
當然
Of course.
你說當然，卻又觸摸地圖
See, you say, "Of course," but then you touch the map.
讓我覺得你不明白我是老大
It makes you think that maybe you didn't realize I was in charge.
鬼爾，是你沒有安全感
Quail, that's your own insecurities in there.
鬼爾？
Quail?
我只是想出一分力幫忙
Okay? I am merely trying to be of service and assisting.
是奎爾
Quill.
我是這麼說啊
That's what I said.
你們該幹一架，看誰是老大
You should fight one another for the honour of leadership.
聽起來很公平
Sounds fair.
-沒必要啦 -不必
- It's not necessary, okay? - It's not.
我有爆能槍，除非你們想用刀子
I got some blasters, unless you guys wanna use knives.
對！拜託用刀子
Oh, yes! Please, use knives.
對，刀子
Yeah. Knives.
我是格魯特
I am Groot.
沒必要
Not necessary.
我們不會拿刀捅來捅去
There shall be no knifing one another.
大家都知道誰是老大
Everybody knows who's in charge.
我
Me.
對吧？
Right?
對，是你
Yes, you.
當然…
Of course! Of course.
當然
Of course.
記住…
Remember...
必須將寶石放回取得的時間
you have to return the stones to the exact moment you got 'em...
否則會引發許多麻煩的替代現實
or you're gonna open up a bunch of nasty alternative realities.
放心，布魯斯
Don't worry, Bruce.
我不會節外生枝
Clip all the branches.
我試過
You know, I tried.
我拿到手套和寶石時，試過救她回來
When I had the gauntlet, the stones, I really tried to bring her back.
我好想她
I miss her, man.
我也是
Me too.
你要的話，我能陪你去
You know, if you want, I could come with you.
你是好人，山姆
You're a good man, Sam.
但這是我的責任
This one's on me, though.
我回來之前別幹蠢事
Don't do anything stupid till I get back.
我怎麼能？
How can I?
愚蠢都被你帶走了
You're taking all the stupid with you.
我會想你的，兄弟
Gonna miss you, buddy.
不會有事的，巴奇
It's gonna be okay, Buck.
這需要多久？
How long is this gonna take?
他需要多久都行，對我們只有五秒鐘
For him, as long as he needs. For us, five seconds.
準備好了嗎，隊長？
You ready, Cap?
回到這裡見，好嗎？
All right, we'll meet you back here, okay?
沒問題
You bet.
進入量子領域，三…
Going quantum. Three...
二…
two...
一
one.
返回現場，五…
And returning in five...
四…
four...
三，二…
three, two...
一
one.
他在哪？
Where is he?
不知道，他迅速經過時間戳記
I don't know. He blew right by his time stamp.
應該回來這裡的
He should be here.
讓他回來
Get him back.
-我在試 -快讓他回來
- I'm trying. - Get him the hell back.
-我說我在試 -山姆
- Hey, I said I'm trying. - Sam.
去吧
Go ahead.
隊長？
Cap?
嗨，山姆
Hi, Sam.
是出了狀況還是進行順利？
So, did something go wrong or did something go right?
把寶石放回去之後，我想…
Well, after I put the stones back, I thought...
或許…
maybe...
我聽東尼的話，好好過日子
I'll try some of that life Tony was telling me to get.
結果如何？
How'd that work out for ya?
很棒
It was beautiful.
我為你高興
Good. I'm happy for you.
真心的
Truly.
謝謝
Thank you.
唯一讓我難過的是
Only thing bumming me out...
我得活在一個沒有美國隊長的世界
is the fact I have to live in a world without Captain America.
Oh.
這讓我想到
That reminds me.
拿拿看
Try it on.
感覺如何？
How does it feel?
好像是別人的
Like it's someone else's.
並不是
It isn't.
謝謝
Thank you.
我會盡力
I'll do my best.
因此它是你的
That's why it's yours.
想跟我聊聊她嗎？
You wanna tell me about her?
不
No.
我想不了
No, I don't think I will.
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-